(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-17T22:37:47.060132",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.8-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
レックウザ生存確認！
Rayquaza vitals confirmed!
始まったよ！始まったよ！
It's started! It's started!
イエーーイ！
Yay!
本日何をするのかと言うと、ホロライブ夏祭りです！
As for what we're doing today, it's the Hololive Summer Festival!
ということで！イエーーイ！
And with that... Yay!
それではまず、お店屋さんの紹介をしていきたいと思います！
So first off, I'd like to introduce our festival stalls!
店屋さん？
Stalls?
まずは、えー、レックウザ生存確認よし！
First up, um, Rayquaza vitals confirmed, good!
あ、レックウザきた！
Ah, Rayquaza's here!
レックウザ！
Rayquaza!
これはハコス流の流しそうめん屋さんです！
This is the Hakos-style flowing somen noodle shop!
いらっしゃい、らっしゃい！いらっしゃい！
Welcome, welcome! Welcome!
いらっしゃい、らっしゃい！流しそうめん準備しておりますた！
Welcome, welcome! The flowing somen is all ready to go!
ナイス！今日はね、ハコスがね、もう大量のそうめんをね、一人で茹でてきてくれたんだよね？
Nice! Today, Hakos boiled a whole bunch of noodles all by herself, right?
すごーい！イエーイ！
Amazing! Woohoo!
はい、そうめん食べたい方はこちら！
Yep, whoever wants somen, come right here!
そして、ヨーヨー屋さんもあります！ヨーヨー屋さんですか？
And we also have a yo-yo stall! How's the yo-yo shop?
はーい！白上フブキです！ヨーヨーあります！
Yes! Shirakami Fubuki here! We have yo-yos!
はい、ということでヨーヨーしたい方は白上ちゃんに声をかけてください！
Alright, so if you want to play with yo-yos, just ask Shirakami-chan!
そして！今スバルのわたあめ屋さんとなってるんですけど...
And! Right now it says "Subaru's Cotton Candy Shop," but...
今日わたあめ屋さんをしてくれるのはこの人！
the person running the cotton candy shop today is this one!
はーい！うちうち、うちだよ！大神ミオだよ！
Yes! Me, me, it's me! Ookami Mio here!
初めてわたあめ作るけど大丈夫かな？
It's my first time making cotton candy, but hope it turns out okay!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Looking forward to having fun with everyone!
イエーイ！やったー！
Yay! Woohoo!
そしてですね、他にもですね、食べ物がたくさん、たこ焼きとか焼きそばとかね、
Also, we have tons of other food, like takoyaki and yakisoba,
りんご飴とかあるんで好きに食べてくださーい！わーい！
and candy apples, so please eat whatever you like! Yay!
そして、今テーブルにいるメンバーまず紹介します！まずは、カリ！
Next, let me introduce the members at the table right now! First is Calli!
はーい、みなさん、森カリオペです！
Hi everyone, it's Mori Calliope!
よろしくお願いしまーす！やったー、夏大好き！
Great to be here! Yay, I love summer!
イエーイ！
Yay!
どんどん回す！そして、アイリス！
Keeping it rolling! Next is IRyS!
Hi! Hi, darlings! Hololive English -Advent-'s ravenous diva, the one and only Nerissa Ravencroftだよ！
Hi! Hi, darlings! Hololive English -Advent-'s ravenous diva, the one and only Nerissa Ravencroft dayo!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ビブーだー！
It's Biboo!
誰から行く？
Who's going first?
What's up?
ビ・ブ・ー！
Bi-boo!
ビブーでーす！
It's Biboo!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ということで、えー、こんな感じでね。
So with that, this is how we're doing it.
あとね、あの全体見る担当の大空スバルです！よろしくお願いしまーす！
And I'm Oozora Subaru, in charge of overlooking everything! Great to be here!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい！それでは好きに楽しんでください！どうぞー！
All right! Please enjoy yourselves however you like! Go ahead!
どうぞー！
Go ahead!
ヨーヨー屋さんやってこ！
Let's check out the yo-yo booth!
えっと、わたあめ何色？
Um, what color cotton candy?
何色にします？
What color would you like?
紫？オッケー！
Purple? Okay!
自分でやってみたいよね
You wanna try doing it yourself, right?
わちゃわちゃするんですけど、あの夏のわちゃわちゃを楽しんでください！
It's gonna be chaotic, but please enjoy the summer festival chaos!
はーい！
Okay!
釣ったことないからな
I've never fished for them before.
ヨーヨー取るぞー！
Let's catch a yo-yo balloon!
何か、魚みたいのいる！
There's something like a fish in there!
魚？この子？この魚、光るやつなんだ！
A fish? This one? This fish is one that glows!
惜しい！
So close!
あと6秒しかない！
Only 6 seconds left!
いけるいける！ああ、見えない！
You can do it, you can do it! Ah, I can't see!
あー、取れた！取れたー！
Ah, caught it! She caught it!
やったー！
Yay!
そうめん流すぞー！
Flowing the somen!
Calliが汁こぼしてて草
Calli spilled the dipping sauce, lol.
I'm so sorry!
大丈夫、大丈夫！
It's okay, it's okay!
大丈夫だって！
It's totally fine!
大丈夫！何とかなる！
It's alright! We'll make it work!
水わーい！
Yay for water!
ここから水びたしになるから...
It's gonna be flooded from here...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
ナイスキャッチ！
Nice catch!
これさ、これないと紙のこよりがもらえないんだよ！
Look, without this, you don't get the paper string!
フブキ先輩、優しくしてくださいよ！
Fubuki-senpai, please go easy on us!
一回一個あげよう、これ！一個！
Let's give them one each! Just one!
いい、大丈夫！好きなの一個！好きなの！
Yeah, it's fine! Pick one you like! Whichever!
いいの？どれにする？
Really? Which one do you want?
すいちゃんが絶対緑、水色選ぶから水色！
Sui-chan would definitely pick green or light blue, so light blue!
これ？じゃあ、もらいます！
This one? Then we'll take it!
釣れたー！
Caught it!
釣れたよー！
We caught it!
それもらうじゃん！
You're just taking it!
釣れました！
Caught it!
どうですか？
How is it?
この見えない糸みたいなのが出てくるからね！
These invisible string-like strands will start coming out!
見えない糸？！
Invisible strings?!
マジで、こうやって... あ、ほら！
Seriously, just like this... Ah, look!
かわいい！イエーイ！
So cute! Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
流すよ！来た来た！
Flowing it down! Here it comes, here it comes!
誰もキャッチできてないから！
Nobody is catching any of it!
キャッチ！取れた取れた！
Catch! Caught it, caught it!
違う違う！濃い濃い！
No no! It's too concentrated!
あったかいよ、この辺！
It's warm around here!
わたあめできてる？
Is the cotton candy forming?
ギャー！溶けてない！
Gyaa! It hasn't melted!
テストでは... テスト、テストではできてたの！テストでは！
In the test... During the test it was working! In the test!
あったかくなるまで時間かかるかも！
It might take some time to heat up!
ナイス！ナイス！
Nice! Nice!
え、これお砂糖入れてから回すんでいいんだよね？
Wait, you turn it on after putting the sugar in, right?
そう！回す！
Right! Spin it!
あっ、怖い怖いです！
Ah, it's scary, it's scary!
まだ溶けてないんだ...
It hasn't melted yet...
キャー！もう一回！
Kyaa! One more time!
何か白いのが出てきた！
Some white stuff came out!
OK, OK. ありがとうございます！
OK, OK. Thank you so much!
ナイスー！
Nice!
マジで？オレンジ欲しい！
Seriously? I want orange!
流れてきた！うわー！
It's flowing down! Whoa!
行け行け！手で！
Go, go! Use your hand!
頑張れ、頑張れ！来た来た！
Hang in there, you got this! Here it comes, here it comes!
いいよいいよ！惜しい！
Looking good, looking good! So close!
頑張れ！落ちてる、落ちてるよ！
Hang in there! It's falling, it's falling!
マジで？！おかわりー！
Seriously?! Refill, please!
じゃ、いきます！
All right, here goes!
お前邪魔なんだよ！
You're in the way!
出てきた！
It came out!
やめて！やめてやめて！
Stop! Stop, stop it!
めっちゃ飛んできた！やばい！
It flew everywhere! Oh no!
何か下手くそ神降臨した！
Looks like the God of Clumsiness has descended!
わたあめが...
The cotton candy...
わたあめ壊れてるんじゃないですか？やめて！
Isn't the cotton candy machine broken? Stop it!
次ネリッサ！ネリッサ！ネリッサは好きなのどうぞ！
Next is Nerissa! Nerissa! Nerissa, pick whatever you like!
怖いですね...
This is scary...
いけるいける！大丈夫！
You can do it! It's okay!
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
うまい、うまい
Nice, nice!
あ、うまい！
Oh, nice!
よーし！さすがマリン船長！
All right! As expected of Captain Marine!
船長、これ取れる？マリン船長！
Captain, can you get this one? Captain Marine!
取れるんじゃなーい？
Should be able to, right?
取れるんじゃない？
I think I can!
流しそうめんより簡単！
This is easier than flowing somen!
あれ？
Huh?
沈む方がやばいって！
Sinking it makes it even worse!
ビビにする？
Go for Bibi?
まだいける、まだいける！
You can still do it, still do it!
頑張れ、頑張れ！
Go for it, go for it!
どっちか選んでください
Please choose one.
落ちます！マリン、どっちにする？
It's falling! Marine, which one?
紫にする？
Go for purple?
うわっ！
Whoa!
マリン、どうする？
Marine, what are you gonna do?
待ってよ、ほら！
Wait, look!
待ってよ、それ！
Wait a sec for that!
あ、入った、入った！
Ah, it went in, it went in!
あ、うま！
Oh, nice!
あ、うまい！
Oh, well done!
なんかちょっとやだ…
I kind of hate this...
なんで？いい感じじゃん！
Why? It looks great!
なんか三角やで
It's kind of triangular.
船長、これいいじゃん！全然！
Captain, isn't this fine? / Not at all!
船長、頑張れ！頑張れ！
Captain, do your best! Hang in there!
ギリギリまでいける！
You can take it right to the limit!
無理？でもいい！
Impossible? But it's fine!
無理、無理、無理！
No way, no way, no way!
切れた！あーーー！
It snapped! Aaaah!
残念！何個取れたの？
Too bad! How many did you get?
0個だよ！
Zero!
手で持った方が…
Holding it with your hands...
両手で持った方がいい！
You should hold it with both hands!
スバルの！
Subaru's!
おいおい、誰がこの町内会のセッティングやったんだ！
Hey hey, who set up this neighborhood festival?!
すいません、ごめんなさい！
Sorry, I'm so sorry!
おいおい！
Hey hey!
えー？どうする？
Eh? What should we do?
あ、いい感じ！
Ah, looking good!
完成？丸くして！
Finished? Make it round!
丸く？あ、破れた！
Round? Ah, it tore!
破れた！
It tore!
見えなーい！
I can't see!
チェリー？めっちゃおいしいけど
Cherry? It tastes really good though!
チェリー？次トワ様！
Cherry? Towa-sama is next!
流しそうめん行きます！
Moving on to flowing somen!
流すよー！
Sending it down!
いくよー！
Here goes!
流したよー！
Sent it down!
トワ様！
Towa-sama!
取れなかった！
I couldn't catch any!
任せて、任せて！
Leave it to me, leave it to me!
あーーー！
Aaaah!
トワ様泣いてる！
Towa-sama is crying!
はい！あげないよ！
Here! I'm not giving it to you!
あ、トワちゃん取っちゃったよ
Ah, Towa-chan took it!
行くぞ、トワ様！
Here we go, Towa-sama!
はい！かわいい！
Yes! So cute!
行くよー！
Here it goes!
きゃーーー！
Kyaaa!
え、ちょっと待って！一本！
Wait, hold on! A single noodle!
一本しか取ってない！
You only got a single strand!
次トワ様流しますよ！
Next, Towa-sama, sending more down!
負けない、負けない！
I won't lose, won't lose!
あーーー！
Aaaah!
へへへ！イエーイ！
Hehehe! Yay!
負けた！
I lost!
トワ様…
Towa-sama...
ヨーヨー釣りよ！
Yo-yo fishing time!
次はビビ！
Next is Bibi!
ビビ！光るとゲーム…
Bibi! If it glows, the game...
オッケー！ノーバディクリア！
Okay! Nobody cleared!
はい、トワ様どうぞ！
Here, Towa-sama, go ahead!
トワが取る！
Towa will get it!
ビビはトワが取る！
Towa will catch Bibi!
やばい！やばい！
Oh no! Oh no!
あーーー！
Aaaah!
トワちゃんも負けて…
Towa-chan lost too...
まあ、ビビがこうやって食べてる間に…
Well, while Bibi is eating like this...
うわ、ロスト！
Whoa, lost it!
おいしい！うま！
Delicious! So good!
光る！ブライト！ブライト！
It glows! Bright! Bright!
光る？これはノーピカピカ？
Glows? This one doesn't glow?
トワちゃん、次お願ーい！頑張ってね！
Towa-chan, next please! Good luck!
頑張ってね！あーーー！
Good luck! Aaaah!
調整ね、取りやすいように
Adjusting it so it's easier to catch.
取りやすいように調整してる！
She's adjusting it so it's easier to catch!
あーーー！
Aaaah!
ビビすくい！
Bibi scooping!
ビビすくい？
Bibi scooping?
あーーー！
Aaaah!
トワ様頑張って！
Towa-sama, you can do it!
トワ様いけるかな？
Can Towa-sama make it?
あ、いける！いける！
Ah, she can, she can!
頑張れ！
Go for it!
アップ、アップ、アップ…
Up, up, up...
オッケー！やったーーー！
Okay! Hurray!
ゲット、ゲット、ゲット！
Got it, got it, got it!
これゲットで！イエーイ！
Got this one! Yay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ビビゲット！
Bibi get!
これトワのじゃないんですけど…
Though this isn't Towa's...
すごい！わたあめ！
Amazing! Cotton candy!
ファーストタイムクリア！
First time clear!
やったーーー！
Yayyy!
ナイスビビトワ！
Nice Bibi Towa!
ナイスビビ！
Nice Bibi!
わー！
Waaah!
ピカピカ！ナイスフライ！
Sparkling! Nice fly!
イエーイ！
Yay!
取れなくてもいいと思うけどね
I think it's fine even without catching it though.
はい！ナイスフライ！
Here! Nice fly!
そうめんにハンバーガー？
A hamburger in the somen?
ジャングルだよ！リンゴ！リンゴ！
It's a jungle! Apple! Apple!
リンゴ！
Apple!
めっちゃクリーン！
Super clean!
オッケー！本当だ！
Okay! It's true!
どこ？ここ、ここ！
Where? Here, here!
いいよ、いいよ！
Looking good, looking good!
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
Biboo Biboo! I won!
あーすごい！Bibooすごいよ！
Ah, amazing! Biboo, that's incredible!
皆さん、ご来店ありがとうございました！
Everyone, thank you so much for stopping by!
なんだろう、ハンバーガー、ピザ、アイス！
What should it be? Hamburger, pizza, ice cream!
またねー！ねるねるねるね！
See ya! Nerunerunerune!
Bye-bye! Thank you, bye-bye!
楽しかった！二人もしんどいね。
That was fun! You two rest up, okay?
わー！はい、Let's go! Let's go!
Whoa! All right, let's go! Let's go!
I know. 次、黄色いくぞ！
I know. Next, here comes yellow!
はい！お、すごいすごい！Biboo...
Okay! Oh, nice, nice! Biboo...
待って、待って、待って！前、前、前！
Wait, wait, wait! Move up, move up!
最初あそこ！あそこ！
First over there! Over there!
うまい、うまい、うまい！やめてー！あー！
Nice, nice, nice! Stop it! Aah!
これでオッケー。
This is okay.
あれ？こぼれてない？大丈夫？
Huh? Isn't it spilling? Are you okay?
こぼれちゃダメだよ！あーオッケー！
Spilling isn't good! Ah, okay!
頑張って掬ってくれ！
Do your best to scoop it up!
緑...黄緑になった！
Just one... It turned yellow-green!
黄緑か。うん。
Yellow-green, huh? Yeah.
It's white!
うん、いい匂い。お菓子作ってる。
Yeah, smells good. Like making candy.
ハンバーガー、ピザ...
Hamburger, pizza...
来たよ！
It's here!
取れ！あー！取れた！
Grab it! Aah! Got it!
ハンバーガー！今のハンバーガー、落ちた？
Hamburger! Did that hamburger just drop?
あと一個はあるよ。
There's still one more left.
うそでしょ！
No way!
見て、水クラゲ作っちゃった！
Look, I made a moon jellyfish!
やばい！やばい！
Oh no! Oh no!
綿あめってこんなことある？
Does cotton candy ever turn out like this?
「今言うなよ」って？鍋みたいなやつ...
"Don't tell me now"? Like a pot...
流しますね。はい！
Sending it down now. Yes!
あー！可愛い！
Ah! So cute!
こぼれちゃう！
It's going to spill!
あ、Bibooも作ってる。
Ah, Biboo is making one too.
言うなよって？
Don't tell me?
なんかメロンパンの味がする。
It tastes somewhat like melon bread.
美味しい。なんかバナナの...
Delicious. Kinda banana-y...
やばいやばい！すごい！
Oh no, oh no! Wow!
ちょっとやばいこれ！
Wait, this is crazy!
一生回るんだけど！
It keeps spinning forever!
ちょっと苦いね。
It's a bit bitter.
でも美味い美味い美味い！重い！
But it's good, good, good! It's heavy!
特にNerissaとBaeがやったことある？
Have Nerissa and Bae in particular ever done this?
家に持って帰る？This one?
Take it home? This one?
Can he cut straight across for his first cut?
そろそろそろそろ...え、嫌だ嫌だ！帰りたくない！
Soon, soon... Wait, no, no! I don't want to go home!
いただきます！
Bon appétit!
でも目論見通りでやばい！
But it went just as planned, crazy!
動いていってる。
It's moving along.
見たことない綿あめ！
I've never seen cotton candy like this!
So you're gonna have a microwave? 嫌だ！
So you're gonna have a microwave? No!
まだそうめん食べる！
I'm still gonna eat somen!
まだそうめん！
More somen!
配信したい！お仕事行かない！
I wanna keep streaming! I'm not going to work!
行くよ！嫌だ！
Here it goes! No!
マイクロウェーブやばい！
The microwave is crazy!
電子レンジ？Popcandy?
Microwave? Popcandy?
イェーイ！コットンキャンディ！
Yay! Cotton candy!
Nerissaさん、Kaelaさん、ありがとうございました！
Nerissa, Kaela, thank you so much!
I will take one. バイバイ！
I will take one. Bye-bye!
またねー！バイバイ！
See ya! Bye-bye!
勝った！紫！オッケー！
I won! Purple! Okay!
落ちたー！
It fell!
多分、easy!
Probably, easy!
オッケー、オッケー！そして...
Okay, okay! And then...
でも、microwave?
But, microwave?
レンジに入れたらちっちゃくなってオッケーです！
If you put it in the microwave, it shrinks, so it's okay!
これ結構疲れる。やばいやばい。
This is pretty tiring. Oh boy, oh boy.
いやでもね、楽しい！楽しい？
But you know, it's fun! Fun?
あー！わたあめが！
Ah! The cotton candy!
どうするのこれ！
What do I do with this?!
くるくる、くるくるして！
Spin it, spin it around!
回して！Biboo!
Spin it! Biboo!
くるくる、くるくるして！
Spin it, spin it around!
Biboo頑張って！またねー！
Do your best, Biboo! See ya!
あー、ちぎれる！
Ah, it's tearing off!
ヨーヨー落ちた！
The yoyo dropped!
わたあめ持って帰っていった。くるくる！
She took the cotton candy home. Spin spin!
ま、夏祭りだからね。雰囲気だけでもね。
Well, it's a summer festival. Even just the vibe.
ベストワンも食べた！
I ate my number one favorite too!
欲しい！
I want it!
もうちょっと、もうちょっと！オッケー、wait wait!
A little more, a little more! Okay, wait, wait!
え、すごい！Bibooさん出来てる！
Wow, amazing! Biboo, you're doing it!
ふわふわ！
Fluffy!
ハンバーガースキ！でも、I'm making a mess.
I like hamburger! But, I'm making a mess.
本当だ！え、難しくない？ディスコードだよこれマジで。
It's true! Wait, isn't this hard? It's discord, seriously.
大丈夫？Very big hamburger please!
Are you okay? Very big hamburger, please!
はい、オッケーです！ちょっと待ってくださーい！
Yes, okay! Please wait a moment!
来た来た来た！あー、流れる！
Here it comes! Ah, it's flowing away!
嫌だ、取れない！取れ取れ取れ！
No, I can't catch it! Grab it, grab it, grab it!
回る回る！
Spinning, spinning!
うわー！
Whoa!
危ない危ない！超えてこい！ここここ！
Watch out, watch out! Cross over! Right here, here!
バーガーが！
The burger!
オッケーオッケーオッケー！甘酸っぱい！
Okay, okay, okay! Sweet and sour!
この後ね、みおちゃんのワンマンですから！
After this, it's Mio's solo live!
あー！時間があるから！
Aah! We still have time!
触らないで！気をつけて！
Don't touch it! Be careful!
20時半からみおちゃんのワンマンです！
Starting at 20:30 is Mio's solo live!
この辺でくるくる...
Spin it around right here...
待って、待って！
Wait, wait!
いいじゃん！だんだん...
Looking good! Little by little...
これでも、あれ、あれ、あれ...
Look at this, whoa, whoa, whoa...
おいおいおい！あー！
Hey, hey, hey! Ahh!
スバル、もう楽しんでる！
Subaru is already having fun!
ヤバい！あー！
Oh no! Ahh!
ちなみにハコスはさ...
By the way, Hakos...
もっと大きい...
Even bigger...
めっちゃさ、夏祭りしたかったらしい。
apparently really wanted to go to a summer festival.
もっと大きいのがいい！
I want a bigger one!
もっとでかい！
Even bigger!
嘘つけ！
Liar!
行くー！
Here I go!
生まれてこの方、夏祭り行ったことないんだって。
She said she's never been to a summer festival in her life.
これ以上でか... そうなの？！
Bigger than this... Really?!
そうだよ。ヤバい、ヤバい。
Yeah. Oh no, oh no.
だからハコスも回って行きたい...
So Hakos wanted to check out the stalls too...
これ、水ポチャした？
Did this fall into the water?
まあまあまあ、大丈夫。一応そうめん屋...
Well, well, it's fine. For now, the somen shop...
終わるから！
will close soon!
本当？
Really?
そうめん屋なんだよ。
It's a somen shop!
いいよ、いいよ。
Nice, nice.
え、待って、ビジューめっちゃ上手くね？
Wait, isn't Bijou super good at this?
待って、オッケー、オッケー、オッケー...
Wait, okay, okay, okay...
オッケー、オッケー、もっと行こうか。
Okay, okay, let's go for more.
ビジューめっちゃ上手いやん！
Bijou, you're super good at this!
オッケー、オッケー。
Okay, okay.
すみません、じゃあそうめんください。
Excuse me, somen please!
まだまだ...
Not yet...
お願いします。
Please!
まだまだ来るよ。
There's still more coming.
はい、どうぞ。
Alright, here you go.
それくるくる、くるくる...
Spin it round, round and round...
くるくる... おー！わー！
Round and round... Whoa! Wow!
できた！
Done!
できたよ！イエーイ！
It's done! Yay!
おー！
Ohh!
オッケー！イエーイ！
Okay! Yay!
ヤバい、これピカチュウで詰まるんだよな、いつも。
Oh no, this always gets jammed on Pikachu.
おー！イエーイ！
Whoa! Yay!
すごい！ありがとう！
Amazing! Thank you!
これちょっと食べます。いただきます。
I'm going to eat this. Thanks for the food!
イエーイ！Very nice, very nice!
Yay! Very nice, very nice!
イエー！フゥー！
Yeah! Whoo!
うま！
Delicious!
すごいなー！えっ、うま！
That's awesome! Whoa, so good!
できた！イエーイ！
Made it! Yay!
ビジュー、ヨーヨー釣りも全部上手いやん。
Bijou, you're good at yo-yo fishing and everything!
すげぇやん！
That's amazing!
美味しかった。そうめん食べる？
That was delicious. Want some somen?
生姜？うん、食べます！
Ginger? Yeah, I'll eat it!
イエーイ！ハコスのさ、ビジュー、スバルが流すからさ、食べなよ。
Yay! Hakos's, Bijou, Subaru will send it down, so go eat it.
二人でさ、一緒にさ。
Both of you, together.
いいの？いいよ。
Can I? Sure!
やっておいで。
Go on, try it out.
しょうがないな。I don't know what you're gonna do with that though.
Guess it can't be helped. I don't know what you're gonna do with that though.
どうやって食べる？溶けない... You want to eat it? Eat it!
How do I eat it? It won't melt... You want to eat it? Eat it!
食べて？食べていいよ。
Eat it? You can eat it.
これ食べてもいいよ。
It's totally fine to eat this.
みんなにここに見せる？コットンキャンディー、ショー、ショー...
Shall we show it to everyone here? Cotton candy show, show...
みんなー！
Everyone!
ほらー！
Look!
Bibooのコットンキャンディーです！
It's Biboo's cotton candy!
綿あめ！
Cotton candy!
綿あめー！
ビジューが取ったヨーヨーも見せて。
Show the yo-yo that Bijou caught, too!
ほら！
Look!
これ？
This?
光るからね！光るから！
It lights up! Because it glows!
すごいやん、ビジュー！ナイス、ナイス！
That's awesome, Bijou! Nice, nice!
じゃあビジュー、今から流しそうめん... じゃあこれ一旦...
Alright Bijou, now flowing somen... Okay, let's put this down for a sec...
あ、オッケー。
Ah, okay.
これ置く場所欲しいね。あー、そうね。
We need a place to put this. Ah, right.
ネリッサが... オッケー、見て。
Nerissa is... Okay, look.
どこかで捨てちゃう？あ、ありがとうございます。
Should we throw it away somewhere? Ah, thank you very much.
いやー！ネリッサ食べんといて！
Nooo! Nerissa, don't eat it!
それビジューのコットンキャンディー！
That's Bijou's cotton candy!
食べたい。うーん、うまいです！
I wanna eat it. Mmm, it's delicious!
うまい？！
It's good?!
ネリッサ、綿あめ作った？You tried?
Nerissa, did you make cotton candy? You tried?
はい。
Yes.
Good?
綿あめは美味しいです。
The cotton candy is delicious.
綿あめ美味しい？
The cotton candy is delicious?
でも、私のスキルですわ。
But as for my skill...
あ、そこ？！
Oh, that's what you mean?!
ちょっと下手です。
I'm a bit clumsy at it.
あ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
大丈夫、楽しめばいいからね。
It's fine, as long as you have fun!
ミオちゃんも...
Mio-chan too...
何その手？
What's with that hand?
Sashimi, sashimi. ウチも綿あめ作ったらできた。
Sashimi, sashimi. I made cotton candy too, and did it.
ねー、汚い、なんか！
Hey, it looks so messy!
よし！
Alright!
なんかやだ。
That looks kind of unappealing.
なんかそれ見せてあげて、ちょっと。
Show them that for a second.
じゃあ、これ... でっかいやつが高画質か。
Well then, this... The big one is high quality, huh.
嫌だ、それやめて！
No, stop that!
やめてよ！やめて、それ見せないで、これ！
Stop it! Stop, don't show this!
綿あめのくずが...
Cotton candy scraps...
ミオちゃん！
Mio-chan!
はい！
Yes!
綿あめ流すけどやる？一緒に。
I'm sending down cotton candy, wanna do it together?
綿あめは流さないで！
Don't send down cotton candy!
綿あめ流すの？
Sending cotton candy down?
ごめん、綿あめは流さない。
Sorry, I won't send down cotton candy.
そうめんを流すのですが、やりますか？
I'm sending down somen noodles, wanna try?
やるか、ウチも食べたいな。
Let's do it, I wanna eat too.
おいでー！そうめんながしな。
Come on over! For flowing somen.
よし、それじゃあいくよ。
Alright, here it comes then.
ちょっと待って、タレない、タレないウチ。
Wait a sec, I don't have sauce, I don't have dipping sauce!
タレ、タレ作って。そこにあるから。
Make some sauce! It's right there.
よいしょ、タレを...
Hup, the sauce...
作りました、ポン酢。
Made it: ponzu sauce.
懐かしい、なんか我が家でした時もさ...
Takes me back... When we did this at my place...
周りの水こうなったなってめっちゃ思う。
I remember the surrounding water ended up just like this.
でしょ？確かに。
Right? Totally.
え、マジこんなんだったよね？
Seriously, it was just like this, right?
そう！めちゃくちゃこうでした。
Yes! It was totally like this.
なった、なった。
It really did.
そいじゃあ...
Alright then...
Oh, it's so wet! Yeah!
ほら！
Look!
Just be careful of this. Yes, okay.
箸当てて。
Get your chopsticks ready.
じゃあ行くよ、二人とも。
Alright, here it goes, you two!
はーい！
Okaaay!
You can do it!
行け、ビジュー！行け、ミオ！
Go, Bijou! Go, Mio!
Woah! Can I take it from anywhere?
Yeah! Okay.
Did you catch it?
はー！あー！
Haa! Aah!
頑張れ！頑張れ！
Hang in there! You can do it!
Nice catch! Yeah! いいぞー！
Nice catch! Yeah! Looking good!
じゃあ行くよ。
Here comes more!
Oh, your turn, your turn!
来い！
Bring it on!
頑張れ！
Go for it!
おおー！わーい！
Ooh! Yay!
うまい！
Nice!
行くよー！
Here it comes!
もっともっと！More, more, more!
More, more! More, more, more!
これズルだよ、みおっちゃん！
That's cheating, Mio-chan!
ダメだよ、これ！
You can't do that here!
ママ、ママが食べるの、これ？
Wait, is this where Mama eats?
いやいや、こっちね、みおっちゃん。参加する人はこっちね、ここ。
No, no, over here, Mio-chan. Participants go over here!
分かった、ごめん。
Got it, sorry!
はい、じゃあもう一回ね。
All right, let's try one more time.
行くよ、GO！
Here it goes, GO!
ナイス！
Nice!
ああー！でもセーフ！
Aah! But safe!
あ、いいやん、いいやん！ナイス！
Oh, not bad, not bad! Nice!
あざっす！捕らえ、捕らえ！
Thanks! Grab it, grab it!
流しまーす、こっち、こっち。
Sending some down! Over here, over here!
あ、みお先輩、一回！
Ah, Mio-senpai, take a turn!
みおたん、みおたん！
Mio-tan, Mio-tan!
来い！来い！
Come on! Come on!
ホッ！おおー！イエーーイ！
Hop! Ooh! Yay!
うわ、美味え！／美味え？
Wow, delicious! / Delicious?
あ！ふわもこ来た！
Ah! FuwaMoco is here!
ふわもこーー！
FuwaMoco!
すごい、お祭りだ！
Wow, it's a festival!
お、美味い？／美味い！
Oh, delicious? / Delicious!
美味しい！
It's so good!
でも、この melt, melt... what is it?
But this melt, melt... what is it?
溶けてる？／溶けてる！
Melting? / Melting!
Look, I made that! I made this one!
でもね、これBibooが作ったんだよ！
But you know, Biboo made this!
えー、すごいね！Bibooちゃん！
Whoa, amazing, Biboo-chan!
どうぞー！／And I want this!
Here you go! / And I want this!
I want that! I want this!
これ、これ、ふわもこ、どうぞー！
Here, here, FuwaMoco, help yourselves!
大丈夫？
Is it okay?
あ、大丈夫？オッケー、オッケー！
Oh, it's okay? Okay, okay!
じゃあ、ふわもこ...
Well then, FuwaMoco...
これ、食べて！
Eat this!
えー、りんご飴！／そう！
Whoa, candy apple! / Yup!
すごい！めっちゃお祭りだけど、いくらですか？
Amazing! It really feels like a festival! How much is it?
めっちゃお祭り！
Totally like a festival!
いくら出せんの？／How much? How much?
How much can you pay? / How much? How much?
いやいや、Biboo, how much this?
No, no, Biboo, how much is this?
え？How much? How much does it cost?
Huh? How much? How much does it cost?
Oh, we don't have any money!
Yeah, I have money! えっと...
Yeah, I have money! Um...
いくらにする？
How much should it be?
10! 10 yen? 10 yen?
100? 100?
流しまーす！／100？流してくれるの？
Sending some down! / 100? Are you sending more?
100！／100万？
100! / 1 million?
100万？100万？
1 million? 1 million?
100万！？
1 million?!
え、じゃあBiboo...
Uh, well Biboo...
あのさ、上手だからさ、代わりにわたあめ作ってあげて！
Hey, you're good at this, so make them cotton candy instead!
Cotton candy! ふわもこ！
Cotton candy! FuwaMoco!
僕が良くなかった、流しますね！
That was my bad, sending it down now!
はい！お願いします！
Yes! Please do!
来い！Biboo上手い！
Come on! Biboo, you're so good!
そう、そう、回して、回して！
Yeah, yeah, spin it, spin it!
おー！美味そう！
Oh! Looks delicious!
オッケー！取った、取った！
Okay! Caught it, caught it!
流していきますよー！／いただきまーす！
Sending them down! / Let's eat!
みおちゃん、どうですか？
Mio-chan, how is it?
美味しいよね！
It's good, isn't it!
流しそうめん、美味っ！
Flowing somen is delicious!
流しそうめん、いいよね！
Flowing somen is so nice!
これ、ちょっと失敗になっていって...
This is kind of turning into a failure...
これが失敗になって...
This is turning into a failure...
大丈夫だよ！大丈夫、今からね、大丈夫だよ！
It's fine! Don't worry, from here on, it'll be fine!
美味しそう！
Looks delicious!
今日ね、マジで箱数ね、死ぬほど茹でてくれたから、いっぱい食べなきゃ！
Today, they boiled an insane amount of boxes, so we gotta eat a lot!
タッパーあるの？／Which one do you want?
Do you have Tupperware? / Which one do you want?
あと、中と大があるのかと思うと...
Thinking there's still medium and large left...
さあ、あと、いっぱいみんなに来てくれることを願うやん！
Now, we just have to hope a lot of people come by!
ね！みんな食べて、みんな食べて！／みんな、いっぱい食べてー！
Yeah! Everyone eat, eat up! / Everyone, eat plenty!
じゃあ、ほっ！取れるかな？じゃあBibooの代わりに...
Okay, hop! Can I get it? Then in Biboo's place...
一番右？
The far right one?
いや、右、左、左！
No, right, left, left!
スバルもそう思ってた！
Subaru was thinking that too!
Oh, it's Lunar!
なんか大丈夫そうかもね！
Seems like it might be okay!
え、でもさ、このレックウザ、今回はみおちゃんに行くんでしょ？
But hey, this Rayquaza is going to Mio-chan this time, right?
音が好き！
I like the sound!
車で来たから持って帰れる！／うわー！
I came by car, so I can take it home! / Whoa!
いいよね！
That's great!
そう、飼い主のみおちゃんのところにレックウザが帰るみたいです。
Yeah, looks like Rayquaza is returning to its owner, Mio-chan.
スタッフさん、ちょっと心配してたよね。「このレックウザ、今日誰か持って帰ってくださるかな」って。
The staff was a bit worried: "Will someone take this Rayquaza home today?"
良かったー！
Thank goodness!
あ、いいやん！後でね！
Oh, that's great! Later, okay?
そうめんはいいじゃーん！
The somen is so good!
行くよ！／Wait, why do you hold them?
Here it goes! / Wait, why do you have them?
流そう！
Let's send some down!
やっと初、フブちゃんが作ってんの？
Finally your first? Fubu-chan, are you making one?
ああー！／できた！
Aaaah! / Done!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
やっただけあって、なんか...
After all that effort, it's kind of...
圧縮綿あめ！
Compressed cotton candy!
圧縮綿あめだったらこれ楽だね！
If it's compressed cotton candy, this is way easier!
なんかこれ削れちゃってさ...
It kind of scraped against the side...
なんかフブちゃん、圧縮綿あめ上手！
Fubu-chan is actually great at making compressed cotton candy!
すごい！スタンプみたい！
Amazing! It looks like a stamp!
ああーー！
Aaaah!
壊れた！
It broke!
でも美味いんです、それみおちゃんにあげなよ！
But it's tasty, go give that to Mio-chan!
え、これ？
Huh, this?
Another white ball!
折れちゃうよ！
It's gonna snap!
ヨーヨー...
Yo-yo...
ヨーヨー運んでくれれば...
If you could bring over a yo-yo...
取れるかな？ヨーヨー...
Can I fish one? A yo-yo...
本当！？
Really?!
あー！詰まってる！
Ah! It's clogged!
I won, Jeremy! I won! I'm going to put them all in!
皆さん、え？
Everyone, huh?
これでございます！
This is what I made!
やばい！あーーーー！
Oh no! Aaaah!
フーちゃんの綿あめ！
Fuu-chan's cotton candy!
ループで繋がってるー！
It's connected in a loop!
上の部分はまだいいんだけどさ...
The top part is fine, but...
I'm going to use every...
これどうやって止めるの？
How do we stop this?!
It's okay, people! Don't panic!
あ、一旦止めたらいい？
Ah, should we stop it for a moment?
I told you it's too much somen!
ジュースみたいになってる！
It's like juice!
フーちゃんごめん！
Sorry, Fuu-chan!
これあれや、ギルティや！
That's definitely guilty!
取れない！これも取れない！
Can't catch it! Can't catch this either!
よいしょ。
Heave-ho.
頑張って！頑張って！
Do your best! Hang in there!
ネリッサこのハンバーガー屋持ち込み...
Nerissa brought food from a burger place...
でも、この色は...
But this color is...
なんで？
Why?
これパテだよ！
This is a patty!
あーーー！パテだこれ！
Ahhh! It's a patty!
どこから入れた？
Where did you put it in from?
ちょっとアグリーカラー...
A bit of an ugly color...
Can we get one more time?
出して！出して！
Take it out! Take it out!
なんだこれ？！
What is this?!
はい！
Here!
スーパーアグリーカラー。
Super ugly color.
Shiori-san, Yo-yo?
それ見せていいんですか？
Are you allowed to show that?
強いオス！
Strong male!
強いオス？
Strong male?
いや、オスメスないから！
No, there are no males or females!
Okay, let's go!
Okay, let's go, let's go!
豚じゃないよ！
That's not pork!
流れてないよ！
It's not flowing!
うわあああああ！
Waaaaah!
Okay, okay!
イエーイ！
Yay!
取った！
Got it!
いやーーー！これこれこれ！
Noooo! This, this, this!
いやーーー！
Noooo!
破れた！
It ripped!
うー、ありがとう！
Ooh, thank you!
持ち替えて！泣かないで！
Switch hands! Don't cry!
泣かないで！
Don't cry!
食べたいよー
I want to eat it~
え、フワモコさー、なんかさ、夏祭りの思い出とかある？
Hey, Fuwamoco, do you have any summer festival memories?
ないです。
We don't.
ない？！
You don't?!
1個だけ、なんか時々日本に引っ越してからは行ってないけど...
Just one... We haven't gone since moving to Japan, but...
あ、そうなんだ！
Ah, is that so!
お祭りは1回しか行ったことなくてー
We've only been to a festival once,
アップルキャンディ...
and apple candy...
りんご飴食べた？
You ate candy apples?
あと、あと...
And, and...
金魚すくいです！
Goldfish scooping!
お願いします、先輩！
Please, Senpai!
金魚すくいやばい！
Goldfish scooping is intense!
それで？
And then?
あー、でもモコちゃんがやってる時に、ちょっと、なんか勢いが強すぎてー
Ah, but when Moco-chan was doing it, she had way too much momentum...
うん。
Yeah.
なんかちょうどその金魚すくいが丘の上、坂の上にあってー
The goldfish scooping stall happened to be at the top of a hill, on a slope...
ああー！
Ah-ah!
モコちゃんが勢いよく、なんかポーンってしたら...
and Moco-chan swung hard and went 'whoosh'...
うん。
Yeah.
金魚のポイの...
The goldfish poi's...
お待たせしました！
Thanks for waiting!
...端っこに付いて、そのまま気付かなくてー
...got stuck on the rim, and without noticing...
うん。
Yeah.
勢いよく、偶然にその水たまりの、足に...
With that momentum, it coincidentally hit someone's foot by a puddle...
きゃーーー！
Kyaaa!
金魚がパチャって...
and the goldfish went splat...
え、やばいそれ！
Wait, that's terrible!
あーって行ったら...
When we went 'Ah!'...
そのまま止まらなくて、なんかその丘にコロコロコロって...
it didn't stop, and went rolling down the hill...
落ちたらその金魚が...
and when it fell, that goldfish...
え、なんでそんな怖いこと言うの？！
Why are you telling such a scary story?!
悲しすぎる思い出...
It's way too sad of a memory...
なんだよこれー！金魚の思い出悲しすぎる！
What is this?! The goldfish memory is way too sad!
できましたー！
It's done!
これからカットしていきます！
Now I'm going to cut it!
やばいそれー！
That looks crazy!
え、ビブーなんか思い出ある？夏祭りの。
Hey, Biboo, do you have any summer festival memories?
Memories of summer festival? Yes.
よいしょ。よいしょー。
Heave-ho. Heave-ho.
あ、花火！
Ah, fireworks!
ファイヤー...何だっけ？ファイヤーワークス！
Fire... what was it? Fireworks!
花火は言ったよね、さっき。
We talked about fireworks earlier.
Fireworks! 花火怖いデス。
Fireworks! Fireworks are scary.
なんで？Why? Why scary?
Why? Why? Why scary?
あ、ビッグサウンド！
Ah, big sound!
あー、ビッグサウンドね！
ビッグサウンド。
Big sound.
バーン！
Boom!
ちょっとバンバンやめて！
Hey, stop banging it!
ねぇ、今さ、今ビブーが話してんのにさ、まじでバンバンバーンってフワモコがもうなんか...
Hey, right now, while Biboo is talking, Fuwamoco is literally going bam-bam-bam...
フワモコやめなさい！暴れるのは！
Fuwamoco, stop it! Stop thrashing around!
ビブー勝つ！勝ったね！勝ったよね！
Biboo wins! You won! You won, right!
これで取ってくれた！
She got it for us!
ビブー、ビブー...
Biboo, Biboo...
ビブーが話してんのに、ビブーが取ってくれたヨーヨーでこうバンバンやってんのやばいだろ、ビブーに向かって！
While Biboo is talking, banging the yo-yo she caught for you towards her like that is crazy!
え、ちなみにフワモコ...
Hey, by the way Fuwamoco...
My glasses!
ヤミーヤミー！嬉しい！
Yummy yummy! We're so happy!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
何の思い出ある？朝の。
What memories do you have?
すいません、これ壊しました。
Excuse me, I broke this.
フワが壊しました、これ！
Fuwa broke this!
上手すぎた？
Was I too good at it?
ヨーヨー、はい！
Yo-yo, here!
これはやばいだろ！
This is ridiculous!
水が黄色...黄色だから、ヨーヨー駄目だったね。
The water was yellow, so the yo-yo didn't work out.
ヨーヨー駄目だったねじゃないよ！
Don't 'the yo-yo didn't work out' me!
フブキ先輩が作って... ヨーヨーのせいだ！
Fubuki-senpai made it... It's the yo-yo's fault!
ヨーヨーのせいじゃないよ！お前が壊したんだろ！
It's not the yo-yo's fault! You're the one who broke it!
そうだぞ！ミオちゃんが一個一個作ったんだぞ！
That's right! Mio-chan made each and every one of them!
ミオ先輩、ありがとうございます！
Mio-senpai, thank you so much!
イエーイ！
Yay!
やったーーー！
We did it!
もう一個！もう一個いいよ！取ってくれますか？
One more! One more is fine! Will you get one for us?
大漁！
Big catch!
ちぎれちゃったから、新しいの取ってもいいですか？
It ripped, so can we get a new one?
もういいよ、いいよー。
Yeah, sure, go ahead.
You're making me go again?
You can take anyone.
You can take any one.
流してあげて！
Send some down for her!
これやばい！
This is crazy!
何色が残ってる？
What colors are left?
これヨーヨー...
This yo-yo...
はい、はい、はい。何にする？
Okay, okay, okay. Which one do you want?
グレープソーダ。
Grape soda.
おー！
Oh!
たぶん。
Probably.
あ、ケチャップだ！
Ah, it's ketchup!
Look at this puppy!
Look at the line! Look at that one, that one!
Which one? Oh, the magenta one!
Which one? Over the line...
綿あめ、どうやって作るんですか？
How do you make cotton candy?
え、まず好きな色を選んで...
Um, first pick your favorite color...
Look, pretty!
何色にする？
What color are you doing?
もうちょっと優しくしてくれる？
Can you be a bit gentler?
えー、でもオレンジ...え、オレンジとか...
Eh, but orange... Like orange...
みおちゃん！
Mio-chan!
はーい！
Yes!
みおちゃん、今日まだ出てない色ある？
Mio-chan, are there any colors not out yet today?
オレンジまだかも。
Orange might not be out yet.
オレンジまだだって。じゃあオレンジにしようか。
Orange isn't out yet, she says. Let's go with orange then.
で、オレンジをこのカップに入れてください。
Now put the orange into this cup, please.
はい！
Okay!
I know, right?
この辺オレンジ行けるだろ。
We can totally go for orange around here.
はい、これで一杯ね、やってください。
All right, give it a full scoop, please.
ほい。
Got it.
大丈夫？
Are you good?
で、この真ん中に入れて...
And put it right into the middle...
リンゴ飴！リンゴ飴、いいよ、食べて！
Candy apple! Here's a candy apple, go ahead and eat it!
You're making that? How's it going?
It's going okay.
入れたらスイッチをオンにして、しばし待つ。
Once it's in, turn on the switch and wait a bit.
Yeah, french fries!
あ、お！え？
Ah, oh! Huh?
えーと、これを...
Um, this...
あ、大丈夫？
Ah, you good?
Oh pizza! And tweet!
Oh, pizza! And a tweet!
ね、コメントで「ヨーヨーで暴れてるの誰？」って言われてるよ。
Hey, chat's asking, "Who's going wild with the yo-yos?"
誰ですか？ヨーヨーで暴れてるの！
Who is it?! Going wild with the yo-yos!
モコちゃんだろ、ヨーヨーで遊んでるの！
It's Mococo, isn't it? Playing with the yo-yos!
暴れてないよ！
I'm not going wild!
それで、こうグルグルグルってして...
And then, you spin it round and round...
もうちょっとね、もうちょっとね。
A little bit more, just a little bit more.
ここに、あの、コットンキャンディ・ティーチャー...
We have our Cotton Candy Teacher right here...
コットンキャンディ・ティーチャー・ビブさんがいるからね。
We've got Cotton Candy Teacher Biboo with us!
ビブ・プロがいるからね。
We have Bib-pro here!
バーガー、プリーズ！リンゴ飴！
Burger, please! Candy apple!
Like beat it, okay. And then wait, yeah?
I don't have scissors! Ow!
We have hasami!
We have scissors!
だってさ、モコちゃん、ずっと...
But Mococo has been...
リンゴ飴美味しい！
Candy apples are delicious!
あ、やっぱ待つしかねえんだ。待つしかないんだね。
Ah, we really just have to wait. Nothing to do but wait, huh?
え、ハコスさんはさ、夏の思い出ある？
Hey Hakos, do you have any summer memories?
夏の思い出？ / 夏祭り、夏祭り！
Summer memories? / Summer festivals, summer festivals!
祭りの思い出ないっしょ。だって日本の夏祭り行ったことないんじゃ...
I don't have festival memories! I've never been to a Japanese summer festival...
そうだ、言ってたわ！うん。よかった。
Right, you mentioned that! Yeah. Glad I asked.
ないよ！止めてない！
There isn't! I didn't stop it!
ちょっと待って、モコちゃん...
Wait a minute, Mococo...
モコちゃん、あのさ、ヨーヨーで暴れるのやめてって言われてる。
Mococo, hey, they're telling you to stop going wild with the yo-yo.
暴れてない！
I'm not going wild!
モコちゃん、モコちゃんこれして！これして！
Mococo, Mococo, do this! Do this!
大丈夫？本当に。モコちゃんやばいよ、本当に。
Are you okay? Seriously. Mococo is out of control, really.
Will you help me? No. Of course I will!
あ、いいね！
Ah, nice!
Yo, look, he already gave up!
これはみおちゃんのエクソシスト...
This is Mio-chan's exorcist...
Look how I'm doing it! I don't know how this happened!
Somehow... I'm going to cry! 回収するぞー！
Somehow... I'm going to cry! / Let's gather them up!
さあ出た出た！出た出た！
Here it comes! It's coming out, it's coming out!
I wanted to make a burger.
That's an egg. I love burgers!
みおちゃん、どうですか？夏祭りは。
Mio-chan, how are you liking the summer festival?
I like hamburgers!
Is it working? あ、なんか出てきた！
Is it working? / Ah, something came out!
グルグル！グルグル！グルグル！
Round and round! Round and round!
ゴロゴロ...
Rolling around...
I need the water, right?
これめっちゃムズいよ、マジで！今んとこビブしか成功してない。
This is super hard, seriously! So far only Biboo has succeeded.
ガチでムズい。
It's seriously hard.
お仕事で、子供のために作った。
For my job, I made them for kids.
え、モコちゃん、綿あめうまいぞ！嘘！えー！
Eh, Mococo is good at cotton candy! / No way! / Woah!
Yeah, I did. Pretty summer.
あとはフリーズ・チェンジ・テクニック... あ、ナイス！ナイス！
And then the freeze change technique... / Ah, nice! Nice!
ナイス！ナイス！
Nice! Nice!
なんでもいいんだよ！
Anything is fine!
Just make what makes you happy.
Don't leave me!
あ、上手！めっちゃ上手いぞ！
Ah, skillful! You're really good at this!
Look at the bun, it makes sense.
あ、ほら！うわー！
Ah, look! Whoa!
ちょっと近づきすぎた、すいません！
Got a little too close, sorry!
やめて！壊れるー！すいません！
Stop! It's gonna break! Sorry!
お！上手い！みおちゃん！
Oh! Nice one, Mio-chan!
はい、できましたー！
All right, it's done!
上手い！すごいねー！
Good job! That's awesome!
みおちゃん、コツは？
Mio-chan, what's the trick?
Oh, it went open!
Oh, it opened up!
紐を濡らさない。
Don't get the string wet.
紐を濡らさない！
Don't get the string wet!
そんなことやめてよ、みおちゃん。紐を濡らさないとかさ。
Don't say stuff like that, Mio-chan. "Don't get the string wet," really?
流しそうめん食べたい！
I wanna eat flowing somen!
流しそうめんね。オッケー。レッツ流しそうめんしよう！
Flowing somen, got it. Okay, let's do flowing somen!
お腹すいたー！お腹すいたよー！
I'm hungry! I'm so hungry!
No no no no no! We have to chew that.
流しそうめんが食べたい？
You wanna eat flowing somen?
お、ちょっとちょっとちょっと...
Oh, wait wait wait...
お願いしまーす！
Please!
スバル流すからねー！
Subaru's sending it down!
すげー！
Awesome!
信用できない？
You don't trust me?
ミオうまいんだよね こういうの
Mio is really good at this kind of thing, huh?
回す 回す 回す
Spin it, spin it, spin it!
すごーい！あ、ここここ
Amazing! Ah, right here, right here!
ほら、ほー！
Look, whoa!
うわー！すごい！できた！
Whoa! Amazing! It's done!
スバルちゃんたちにも持ってこう
Let's bring some to Subaru and the others too!
いやいやいや、水やばそう
No, no, no, the water looks dangerous!
ほら！
Look!
そこにあの、つゆを入れて
Put the dipping sauce in there.
綿飴うま！
The cotton candy is so good!
あ、麺通す？
Ah, should we send down the noodles?
はい、プレゼント！
Here's a present for you!
落とすなよー
Don't drop it!
わー
Whoa!
吸うの苦手すぎるだろ！
You are so bad at slurping!
あ、はじめきた！はじめー！
Ah, Hajime is here! Hajime!
はじめちゃん！
Hajime-chan!
はじめちゃんだよー
It's Hajime-chan!
傘さして
With an umbrella...
よし、ナイス！
All right, nice!
うわー、ナイス！
Whoa, nice!
ミオちゃんこれ流してあげて
Mio-chan, send this down for them.
お、すごい！うわー！
Oh, amazing! Whoa!
ナイス！
Nice!
今日はダンスレッスン...
Today is dance lesson...
流すよ！そうめん！
Sending it down! Somen!
GO! GO!
じゃ取って、なんか先まで
Then catch it at the bottom!
オッケーオッケー
Okay, okay!
ナイスキャッチ！
Nice catch!
はい！
Here!
はい、そうめん！
Here's the somen!
順番に並んでね
Line up in order!
ナイスキャッチ！ナイスキャッチ！
Nice catch! Nice catch!
Wait, do you want it? Put it in.
きゃー！
Eek!
Okay, let's go!
いくぞ、そうめん！
Here it comes, somen!
そうめん！
Somen!
うまい！
Delicious!
これいい肉だね
This is good meat, huh?
これやべてぇ、これ
This is crazy good!
やばい、箱食いしてる！
Oh no, she's eating straight from the box!
ハコス、これで食ってる！
Hakos is eating it right like this!
Okay, okay, Moco-chan, this is for you.
さすがだな
As expected!
Thank you!
え、あのヨーヨーやって！はじめ！
Hey, go do the yo-yo, Hajime!
え、待ってお腹いっぱい
Wait, I'm so full!
いっぱい？
Full?
イカちゃん、浸して、どれでもいいよ
Ika-chan, soak it, any of them is fine!
Also, wow. That smells like ketchup.
I'm making the hamburger, man.
うまい！
Delicious!
はい、食べていいよ
Yes, you can eat it.
だめ？頑張れ！ねねち頑張れ
No good? Hang in there! You got this, Nenechi!
どう？
How is it?
うーん！おいしー！
Mmm! It's so good!
よかったー
Thank goodness!
すごく美味しいね、よかったー
It's super delicious, thank goodness!
いけるかはじめ？オッケー
Can you do it, Hajime? Okay.
はじめは今ね、
Right now, Hajime is...
やってみよう！とりあえずやってみよう！
Let's give it a try! Let's just try it!
なんか、もさもさしたやつが光るやつ
The fuzzy one is the glowing one.
そう、もさもさしてるのが取れるやつね
Yeah, the fuzzy ones are the ones you can catch.
あ、あ、おお！取れた！
Ah, ah, oh! You got it!
取れたよ！
I got it!
まあまあ、ナイスナイス！
Alright, alright, nice, nice!
2個取れてる！
You got two!
ねねちきたー！
Nenechi is here!
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
釣れた！
Caught it!
ナイス！ナイス！景品！
Nice! Nice! Here's your prize!
え、これ飛んでった？
Huh, did this one fly out?
いいよいいよ、持って帰ってそいつ
It's fine, it's fine, take that one home!
指にはめてね
Put it on your finger!
回す？
Spin it?
回せ、ねねね！
Spin it, Nene-ne!
切れるだろお前！負荷かかりすぎてる！
It's gonna snap! You're putting way too much force on it!
ちぎれちゃった
It tore off!
ちぎれたー！
It snapped!
わっしょい！わっしょい！
Wasshoi! Wasshoi!
ギブ、ギブアップ！
Give, give up!
ようこそー！
Welcome!
流そう、流そう！
Let's send them down, let's send them down!
I'm determined now, I have to finish this.
Yeah.
大丈夫、死ぬほど水あるから
Don't worry, we have crazy amounts of water!
流しそうめんくださーい！
Flowing somen, please!
流すのだー！
Sending it down!
食べるな、食べるな
Don't eat it yet, don't eat it!
あれ、バーガーパン？
Huh, is that a burger bun?
うわー、めっちゃ作れてる！
Whoa, you made so much!
すごーい！マジで！？
Amazing! Seriously?!
すごい出来がいい！
It turned out so well!
めっちゃ可愛い！
It's so cute!
いいね！
Looking good!
私はアメリカ人です。バーガーが好きですー。
I am American. I like burgers.
何もつけないハンバーガー
A plain hamburger with no toppings.
あ、そうなんだ
Ah, is that so?
え、ねねち、後で綿飴作ってよ。めっちゃこれ面白いよ
Hey, Nenechi, make cotton candy later! It's so much fun!
あ、行くな、固めんぞー
Ah, don't leave, they're gonna clump up!
はじめにも作ってほしいわ
I want Hajime to make some too.
I'm trying.
こっちか？
This way?
I don't think we have tape.
はい、作るわ
Alright, I'll make it.
じゃあどうぞ！
Here you go!
はい、流しまーす！
Alright, sending it down!
来い来い来い来い！
Come on, come on, come on!
元気すぎるだろ！
You're way too energetic!
やったー！ただ飯だー！
Yay! Free food!
美味しい！
Delicious!
めっちゃ腹減ってた
I was starving!
グミ作りたい
I want to make gummies.
グミ？
Gummies?
流してください！
Please send some down!
来い来い来い！
Come on, come on, come on!
Dolphin? Yeah! ああ！
Dolphin? Yeah! Ah!
お、うまい、うまい、うまい！めっちゃうまい！
Oh, nice, nice, nice! That's so good!
来たら出てくるから、ほら、中。
It'll come out once it's ready, see, inside.
そしたら、グルグル...
And then you swirl it...
おー！
Oh-!
そう、あったかくなるまで時間がかかる。
Yeah, it takes time until it heats up.
アイス屋さん、もう... そう、かかる時間。
Ice cream shop, already... Yeah, it takes time.
一番うまいのは、ビブ...
The best one is Biboo...
あーーー！
Ahhh!
え、こっちは？ 落ちちゃった。
Eh, what about here? It dropped!
どっちのほうがいいですか？アイスか、グミ、どっち作ったほうがいいですか？
Which one would you prefer? Ice cream or gummies, which should I make?
行っちゃう！全部行っちゃう！
It's going! They're all going!
あ、入った！
Ah, it went in!
狙って！５、４、３...
Aim! 5, 4, 3...
飛ばす！
Send it!
アイスか、グミ...
Ice cream or gummies...
来た来た来た！うまいやん！めっちゃうまい！
Here it comes! Nice! That's so good!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ティッシュが...
The tissue is...
オッケーです！
It's okay!
あー！閉じないで！
Ah! Don't close it!
これ、これ！ボタン！
This, this! The button!
待って！待ってください！
Wait! Please wait!
ちょっと待って！どっちがいいですか？アイス...
Wait a second! Which do you want? Ice cream...
...か、グミ？
...or gummies?
来い、来い、来い！アイス！アイス！
Come on, come on! Ice cream! Ice cream!
おい、こら、こら！
Hey, whoa, whoa!
今、待って！
Wait right now!
ネリッサかわいいじゃなくて、アイスかグミか教えて！
Not "Nerissa is cute"—tell me, ice cream or gummies?!
えっ、キャンディー包丁？キャンディー包丁？
Eh, candy knife? Candy knife?
はい、はい、はい！
Yes, yes, yes!
なんかね、あー...
You know, ah...
いくつになってもね、アイスうまいよ。アイス？
No matter how old you get, ice cream's delicious. Ice cream?
みんなグミがいいんだって！クルクル、クルクル！
Everyone says gummies! Swirl it, swirl it!
クルクル、クルクル...
Swirl, swirl...
黄色いのが飛んでる！わたあめ！
Yellow stuff is flying! Cotton candy!
グルグル、グルグル...
Round and round, round and round...
ヤバい、ヤバい、ヤバい！
Oh no, oh no, oh no!
ヤバいって、マジ！ヤバい！
Seriously, this is crazy! Oh no!
わたあめ！わたあめが！
Cotton candy! The cotton candy!
ちょっと待って、わたあめ会場盛り上がりすぎ！
Wait a minute, the cotton candy booth is getting way too wild!
ちょっと待って！ヤバいよ！ヤバい！
Wait a sec! This is bad! It's crazy!
あー！ヤバい！
Ah! Oh no!
マジで頑張れ！もう手を躍らすんだ！もっと躍らすんだ、手を！
Seriously, hang in there! Make your hand dance! Move your hand more!
I want a sushi umbrella! すしアンブレラ？
I want a sushi umbrella! A sushi umbrella?
ゆっくり、ゆっくり... もうちょっとゆっくり...
Slowly, slowly... A little slower...
下から... あーーーー！
From below... Aaaah!
誰か助けて！あああああ！
Someone help! Aaaaaah!
えっ、えっと...
Uh, umm...
回さないで！回さないで、わたあめ機！それスバルが持って帰るやつだから！
Don't spin it! Don't spin the cotton candy machine! Subaru's taking that home!
えっ、えっと、えー、みんな...
Uh, umm, well, everyone...
きゃあああああ！
Kyaaaaaah!
どうしたらいいの！？誰か助けて！どうしたらいいの、これ！笑ってないで！
What should I do?! Someone help! What do I do with this?! Stop laughing!
機械壊す、やめろ！機械壊すな！誰か助けて！
You'll break the machine, stop! Don't break the machine! Someone help!
OK, let's do this! わー！うわー！
OK, let's do this! Waaah! Uwaaah!
取れちゃった！終わっちゃった、これ！
It came off! It's finished!
ええええええ！？何これ！？
Eeeeeh?! What is this?!
Bibooの手が... Nerissa, Nerissa... あーーー！
Biboo's hand is... Nerissa, Nerissa... Aaaah!
飴！流しそうめんお願いしまーす！
Candy! Nagashi somen, please!
行きますよ、ちょっと見てたほうがいいんじゃない？バーガーアンド...
Here we go, shouldn't you watch for a sec? Burger and...
これコーラつき？コーラつき？おー、コーラつき！
Does this come with cola? With cola? Oh, with cola!
全てがね、揃ったね。スーパー知育菓子！
Everything's here! Super educational candy!
そして、ハジメの作った... これは何ですか？
And the one Hajime made... What is this?
やったー！わたあめです。いただきます。
Yay! It's cotton candy. Let's dig in.
すごい！これはBibooアタック...
Amazing! This is Biboo attack...
じゃあ、食べてみてください。いただきます。
Well then, please try eating it. Bon appetit.
ん？何か固くて...
Hm? It's kind of hard...
粘土みたいになるんだ。わたあめって...
It turns into something like clay. Cotton candy...
すごいね！噛めないでしょ？
That's crazy! You can't chew it, can you?
え、噛めない、これ？ Biboo Teacher, 1 point! ナイス、ナイス、ナイス。
Eh, you can't chew this? Biboo Teacher, 1 point! Nice, nice, nice.
100 points.
おお、えー？何ポイントこれ？
Oh, huh? How many points is this?
Uh... 2 points.
ああ...
Ah...
マジ？吹っ飛んでもいいけど...
Seriously? Well, you can blow it away...
10 points.
あづ！
Hot!
優しい！
So sweet!
優しい！カインドスイッチャー！カインドスイッチャー！
So kind! Kind switcher! Kind switcher!
I gave you 10 points, though.
えー、綿飴欲しいなあ！
Aw, I want some cotton candy!
Welcome.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
いただきます！食べ尽くせ！
Thanks for the food! Devour it all!
え、なんか煙出てる！
Wait, there's smoke coming out!
あ、今オフになってる！
Ah, it's turned off right now!
ちょっと待って！え、綿飴屋一回止めます！
Hold on! Uh, we're pausing the cotton candy shop for a moment!
ごめんなちゃい
Sowwy!
やばい、ねねち！初っ端綿飴機ぶっ壊したかも！
Oh no, Nenechi! I might've broken the cotton candy machine right off the bat!
えええー？！
Whaaat?!
ごめんなちゃい
Sowwy.
やばい、煙やばい！
Oh no, the smoke is crazy!
あ、見ちゃったよ！
Ah, I saw it!
煙？
Smoke?
今あの、それ危ないんで、放送中断でこれ。
That's dangerous right now, so we're interrupting the broadcast.
あ、メンテ、メンテ...
Ah, maintenance, maintenance...
あ、メンテナンス...
Ah, maintenance...
でもね、飴入れた直後煙出てたよ。
But smoke came out right after putting candy in.
あ、じゃあ大丈夫か！じゃあ大丈夫。もうちょっといけるやろ。
Ah, then it's fine! It's fine. It can keep going a bit.
美味しい！
Delicious!
あ、それONになってる！ONになってる！
Ah, it's on! It's on!
あ、ONになってた！OFFになってた！
Ah, it was on! Wait, it was off!
あ、そうだね。
Ah, that's right.
オッケーオッケー、じゃあ綿飴屋さんちょっと1回休止です。メンテナンス入ります！
Okay, okay, the cotton candy shop is paused for a moment. Going into maintenance!
メンテナンス入ります！
Undergoing maintenance!
まあまあまあまあ...
Now, now, now, now...
ごちそうさまでした！美味しかった、一口！
Thanks for the meal! That one bite was delicious!
棒状のやつ...
The stick thing...
うわあ！
Whoa!
焼きそば...
Yakisoba...
Yakisoba yummy!
Oh, no!
Cotton candy... Cotton candy...
No way! I'm scared!
You did that!
You ate whole yakisoba that one time! That one time in my life!
It's yummy!
ごちそうさまでしたってこと？
Does that mean she's all done?
おい！
Hey!
やばい！来い、来い！
Oh no! Come on, come on!
ストレートでいけるから。
You can do it straight.
ねねち、いける？
Nenechi, can you do it?
いけないかも...
I might not be able to...
がんばれ！
Hang in there!
ねね、がんばれ！
Nene, do your best!
いけないかも...
I might not be able to...
それちなみにミオちゃんと、あの、ビブーは成功したの。
By the way, Mio-chan and Biboo succeeded at that.
なんで？！どうやって？！
Why?! How?!
聞いたらね、『えー』ってなるよ。
If you hear how, you'll go, 'Ehh?!'
If you're going to feed it to someone else, not a good idea.
がんばれ、ねねち！
Go for it, Nenechi!
I have to eat it.
うちら実力で取ってたぞ、ちゃんと。
We properly caught it with our own skill, you know.
あ、2個！2個獲り！2個獲り！あー！
Ah, two! A double catch! A double catch! Ahh!
やっぱ欲張ると良くないね。
Greed really isn't good, after all.
欲張ると良くないね。もう1回いいよ。
Greed isn't good. You can try one more time.
やったー！
Yay!
もう1回いいの？優しい！
One more time? So kind!
もう1回いいよ、もう1回。
You can try again, one more time.
これちなみにミオちゃんが全部手作りしたから。
By the way, Mio-chan made all of these by hand.
すごい！
Amazing!
だからドーンっていれたわけじゃないっしょ？大丈夫。
So it's not like you slammed it in, right? It's fine.
はい、そうめん屋いらっしゃい、いらっしゃい！
Alright, welcome to the somen stand, welcome!
えーっと、ポテト！
Umm, potato!
わかりました！流します！
Got it! Flowing it down!
ポテト？
Potato?
焼きそば、焼きそば行く？
Yakisoba, want yakisoba?
手で取ればいいよ！
Just grab it with your hands!
ここを信じて！
Trust in this spot!
ナイス、ナイス、ナイス！取れた！
Nice, nice, nice! You got it!
もう1個！もう1個！
One more! One more!
気をつけて！
Be careful!
パチパチたこ焼きが、綿飴機...
The crackling takoyaki in the cotton candy machine...
噛んじゃった、噛んじゃった！喉入った！
I bit it, I bit it! It went down my throat!
おもちゃの...
The toy...
やったー！
Yay!
取れなかったよ、もう。
I couldn't get it at all, jeez.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
好きな色取ってね。
Pick your favorite color.
Okay, yay. I don't want to pick blue. I like pink.
ワイド、ワイド、ワイドだから大丈夫。
Wide, wide, it's wide so it's fine.
スライストーストにあっち...
Sliced toast over there...
猫が喜びそう。
Cats would probably love that.
確かにな。
True that.
これやめなさい！このバシバシバシバシやめなさい！
Stop that! Stop slapping it like that!
またバシバシしてる！
She's slapping it again!
共鳴、共鳴。
Resonance, resonance!
お！燃えた？
Oh! Did it burn?
え、これ...
Wait, this...
こっちまで行っちゃってる！
It went all the way over here!
あらららら。
Oh dear, dear, dear.
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
ねえ、鯖可愛い。
Hey, the mackerel is cute.
終わった？
Is it over?
え、そこからね、回収されてまたね、そうめんになる。
Uh, from there it gets retrieved, and then it becomes somen again.
無限そうめんや。
Infinite somen.
はい！
Yes!
Excuse me, cotton candy bar!
お客様？
Dear customer?
三度目のマナーがありますからね。
There's manners for a third visit, you know.
お客様？
Dear customer?
お客様、気をつけてね！
Dear customer, please be careful!
はい！
Okay!
ここからね、こうだよ。
From here, do it like this.
これ壊さないでね！
Don't break this, okay?!
壊さないで始め、Don't break, okay?
Start without breaking it! Don't break, okay?
頑張って！
Do your best!
おっ！
Oh!
Oh no! Yeah!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
異常なし！
No abnormalities found!
Thank you. I'll share with people.
Wait, my hands are going in it.
Okay, I like your fingers.
Your fingers in my mouth? Great.
流しそうめん... あ、チーズだからね。
Nagashi somen... Ah, because it's cheese.
チーズの匂いする。
It smells like cheese.
流しそうめん
Nagashi somen.
え、臭いの？
Wait, does it stink?
キャンディだけどチーズの匂い。
It's candy, but it smells like cheese.
キャンディだけど？本当だ！
Even though it's candy? It really does!
Not yet.
でも、スバルが食べないからネリッサちゃんが食べてくれる？
Subaru won't eat it, so Nerissa, will you eat it?
取れなかった！
I missed it!
I'll eat this later.
Yeah, eat it later! Eat this!
めっちゃ嗅いでる、嗅いでる。マジやばいって。
She's totally sniffing it. That's seriously crazy.
流した！
Sent it down!
ちょっと無くした？
Did you lose some?
Oh!
あれ無くした？
Did that get lost?
フブキ、ヨーヨー無くしたの？
Fubuki, did you lose the yo-yo?
初っ端のヨーヨーが無くなった。
The very first yo-yo disappeared.
流しそうめん
Nagashi somen.
フブキ先輩、もっとお願いします！
Fubuki-senpai, more, please!
あれ、ヨーヨー消えたんで、後でもう1回やってください。
Wait, the yo-yo vanished, so please try again later.
やっちゃった！
Did it!
え、一緒に輪っか...
Wait, the loop together...
ラッキーだね！ラッキー、ラッキー！
That's lucky! Lucky, lucky!
綿あめ機は壊れ...
The cotton candy machine broke...
もう1回、もう1回！
One more time, one more time!
大変なことになってる。
It's gotten out of hand.
え、この紐フブキ先輩... はい、おしまい！
Wait, this string, Fubuki-senpai... Okay, all done!
あー！落ちた！
Ah! It dropped!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
Do you want to make it together?
Okay. うちもやってみたい！
Okay. I want to try too!
Here's the pizza.
わんこそば？
Wanko soba?
I'm going to probably use... Where's the little spoon? Where's the little spoon?
わんこそばだな。わんこそばを言ったらいいね。
That's wanko soba. Better call it wanko soba.
I put it in the garbage, it was dirty.
Okay. Why do you want it?
'Cause people are going to make it together.
綿あめを回転させよう！
Let's spin the cotton candy!
Open wide.
オレンジ。はい。
Orange. Yes.
Oh, wait, you didn't open it. Never mind.
It might be hard to get together.
That's okay, you can keep it, I'll play with my toy.
そして、どうかな？
And how is it?
やったことある？あるある。
Have you done this before? Yeah, yeah.
You can join in!
飴やりたい。
I want to do candy.
The balls are harder.
優しくね、優しくね。
Gently, gently.
壊すわけないし、失敗するわけないんだから！
There's no way I'll break it or fail!
ちょろい！
Piece of cake!
Nerissa, do you want some somen?
I'm just going to steal it from Bae's side.
うわー！
Whoa!
大丈夫、大丈夫。
It's okay, it's okay.
やった、セーフ！
Yay, safe!
やったー！
Yay!
Yeah!
Oh, that was so wet!
これやりたい！
I want to do this!
本当に匂いする。
It really smells like it.
Smells like bacon.
縁日だって、遊びてえよ！そうだよな！
It's a festival, I wanna play too! Totally!
うわー！
Whoa!
Yeah, the ketchup...
やばっ！やばい！
Oh crap! Crazy!
玉！
The ball!
I'm done.
とり、とり！
Take it, take it!
ヒュー！
Whoo!
あ、いいね！
Ah, nice!
フブキ先輩すごい！
Fubuki-senpai is awesome!
Don't break it!
And it's done.
You know there's so many steps?
This one has even more steps, look at that!
I can't do that!
Yes you can, you just have to commit.
やったー！
We did it!
これ何？
What's this?
へー、マジで...
Huh, seriously...
かわいい！夏祭りだからね。
Cute! It's a summer festival after all.
できた！かわいい！
It's done! Cute!
これで行ったよ。
It went with this.
2文字、5文字自己紹介してもうて。
Give a 2-word, 5-word self-introduction.
おいしい！
Delicious!
おいしい、屋台の...
Delicious, food stall...
I need to use my hands, okay?
めっちゃ天かすの匂い！
It smells so much like tempura scraps!
これね！
This, right!
I need to do this.
Ew, I don't like how it feels.
Now the bacon.
I need to cut it into pieces.
屋台のキラキラ。きれい！
Festival glitter. Pretty!
Yay! It feels weird.
やった！
Yay!
これヤバいよ！
This is crazy!
あー！
Aah!
Ready? Ready?
これチクチク系？え、ごちゃ混ぜ？
Is this the spiky kind? Wait, mixed together?
あ、そうそう！
Ah, yeah yeah!
ベー、混ざってる？ベー、混ざってない？
Bae, is it mixed? Bae, isn't it mixed?
冷え冷えのそうめんいくぞ！
Here comes the ice-cold somen!
ベー、そうめんください！
Bae, give us somen, please!
イエーイ！
Yay!
うわー！でもチーズのがヤバい、これ！
Whoa! But the cheese one is crazy!
ストロベリーのほうが良かったんじゃない？
Wouldn't strawberry have been better?
キャンディ、これ！
This is candy!
なんかボロボロになっちゃう！
It's, like, crumbling apart!
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ちょっと待って！あー！
Wait a second! Ahh!
ヤバいヤバい！
Oh no, oh no!
大丈夫！
It's fine!
ちゃんと回収して！ちゃんと回収して！
Collect it properly! Collect it properly!
え、今わたあめ作ってんの誰？
Wait, who's making cotton candy right now?
ナナ～！
Nana~!
ちゃんと回収してね！
Make sure to collect it!
回収して！
Collect it!
これ？
This?
いや、うまい！
No, you're good at this!
大きくなってきた！
It's getting bigger!
うまい！
Nice!
上手上手！
Good job, good job!
この真ん中めっちゃ熱いから！触ったら...
The center is super hot! If you touch it...
ジュってなるから！
...it'll sizzle!
それで固くなってきた！
And it's hardening up like that!
すごい！すごーい！
Awesome! So cool!
足りないでしょ！
That's not enough, right!
早く回収しないと！
Hurry and collect it!
It smells...
What is that smell?
It smells like bacon!
Bacon?
Candy?
大丈夫、Don't worry.
It's okay, don't worry.
You guys are so funny.
I can smell it from here, and I'm like eight steps away!
Right? It smells...
重くなってきた！
It's getting heavy!
おー、すごい！すごいっしょ！
Ooh, awesome! Pretty cool, right!
なんかすごい尖ってきた！
It's getting really pointy!
普通にちょっとだけ見える。
I can actually see a little bit.
割れちゃった！
It broke!
でもわた...わたが...
But the cotton... the cotton candy is...
Where's the cups? Where's the cups?
そうめん入ってないよ！
There's no somen in there!
しょうがない、取って取って！
Can't be helped, grab it, grab it!
三角形になってきた！
It's turning into a triangle!
おかしい！丸くして！
That's weird! Make it round!
前進しすぎてるのよ！
You're leaning forward too much!
おー！すごいすごい！
Ooh! Amazing, amazing!
あ、これね...
Ah, this one...
食べてくださいよ！
Please eat it!
I think they count...
なんだこれ！
What is this?!
あー！
Aah!
Hot dog!
バイバオ！
Bye-bye-o!
Look, you said... but look, it's not getting...
薬味入れるや...
Add the condiments...
It's harder... It keeps falling...
It smells bad! It smells bad!
え？何？
Eh? What?
ま、やっぱり燻んでるかもしれない...
Well, it might be smoking after all...
焦げてる！
It's burning!
えええーーー！
Ehhhh?!
Bae, is that...? Bae, wait, what is that?!
わたあめ、キバついて...
The cotton candy got fangs...
あーー！おい、何やってんだ！
Aah! Hey, what are you doing?!
Where are the cups for this?!
流しそうめん！
Nagashi somen!
我がそうめん屋が！我がそうめん屋が！
Our somen shop is—! Our somen shop is—!
止めてくださいね！
Please stop it!
そうめん屋するよ！
I'll run the somen shop!
カップないて！俺チーク屋やで！
There are no cups! I'm the cheek blush shop!
お前チーク好きすぎるだろ！
You like cheek blush way too much!
そうめん入れとくよ！
I'm putting somen in!
こっちの代わりに、どれがいい？
Instead of this, which one do you want?
I don't know! I don't know! They're the same thing.
Pink one! Pinkね。
The pink one! Pink, right.
ピンクやりたい！バイバーイ！
I wanna do pink! Bye-bye!
これにしよ！
Let's go with this!
一緒に、そんな匂いするピザ作る？
Wanna make a pizza that smells like that together?
あ、本当だ！めっちゃチーズの匂い！
Oh, really! Such a strong cheese smell!
匂い嗅いでみて！
Try smelling it!
このチーズクッキーを...
This cheese cookie...
真ん中！
In the middle!
あ、そう。でもキャンディだけど、すごいリアルの匂いです。
Ah, yeah. But even though it's candy, it smells so realistic.
曲がっちゃった！
It got bent!
いやー...
Man...
チーズの匂い嗅いだ！
I smelled the cheese!
ベーコンもしっかり、ベーコンの...
The bacon too, definitely smells like bacon...
ヤバい！なんかコーンとか野菜の匂いもしてきた！
Oh no! Now it smells like corn and veggies too!
よし、オペレーションしよう！
Alright, let's do an operation!
あれがチーズ？
Is that cheese?
そう、これがチーズで...
Yeah, this is cheese...
I figured it out! Smell it! It's not bad!
まあ！
Oh my!
デカすぎるんだ！
It's way too big!
でかいのよ！
It's huge!
流すよ！あーー！
Sending it down! Aah!
色落とすんかい！可愛い！
Dropping the color?! Cute!
本当はこれ作りたかった！
I actually wanted to make this one!
流したそうめん取って食べて！
Grab the somen sent down and eat it!
そうだよ！
That's right!
オッケー！
Okay!
じゃあこのわたあめ持ってるね。
Then I'll hold this cotton candy.
あやめもアイスクリーム！
Ayame gets ice cream too!
わたあめ似合うね！
Cotton candy suits you!
両手で回収したほうがいい！
Better collect it with both hands!
欲張りだなー！
So greedy!
へい、取ったわ！
Hey, I got it!
あ、上手いね！
Oh, you're good!
流しそうめんの才能あるね！
You've got a talent for nagashi somen!
いえーい！
Yay!
ヤバい、またヨーヨーキッズが暴れてる！
Oh no, the yo-yo kid is going wild again!
よいしょ！
Heave-ho!
おー！美味いね！美味いね！
Ooh! Nice! Good job!
まだ行こう、まだ行こう！
Let's keep going, let's keep going!
これ落ちてても食べないと！
You've gotta eat it even if it falls!
ねー！
Right!
あーーー！
Ahhhh!
器用なんだわ！
She's nimble!
器用だねー、これなかなか！
She's pretty nimble at this!
あ、お箸...
Ah, chopsticks...
おい、よいしょ！
Hey, heave-ho!
あーーー！
Ahhhh!
はい、みこちこれチーク返し！
Here, Mikochi, returning your cheek blush!
あ、サンキュー！
Ah, thank you!
あー！あー！あー！
Ah! Ah! Ah!
ザ・ゴーストが一生懸命言ってたから感想言ってあげて！
The Ghost was speaking so earnestly, tell her your impressions!
あーーー！
Ahhhh!
すごい！あーーー！
Amazing! Ahhhh!
え、いやー！すごい！
Whoa, amazing!
美味しそう！
That looks delicious!
3個目だ！めっちゃ掛ける！
That's the third one! You're putting so much on!
ああー！
Aaah!
分かりました！
Understood!
きゃー！イェーイ！
Kyaa! Yay!
あ、できた？
Ah, is it done?
イェーイ！
Yay!
きゃー！
Kyaa!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
おい、暴れキッズだ！
Hey, it's a rampaging kid!
ヨーヨーキッズ大暴れ！大暴れ！
The yo-yo kid is going wild! Wild!
Whoa, whoa, my hands are dirty!
おい、お前、お前よ！
Hey, you, cut it out!
Someone's touching my fingers, wait!
I would.
夏祭りの思い出！
Summer festival memories!
オッケー、うーんと...
Okay, umm...
That's for Mococo-chan and the...
夏祭りの思い出出して！
Share a summer festival memory!
仕上げ、キラキラ...
The finishing touch, sparkle...
それ最近じゃん！
That was just recently!
I skipped a step, so... okay.
もっとキラキラ！バーン！
More sparkle! Baaam!
え？え？
Eh? Eh?
めちゃくちゃ光ってる！
It's glowing like crazy!
たこ焼き熱すぎだろ！
The takoyaki is way too hot!
溢れてる、たこ焼きが！
The takoyaki is overflowing!
つ、ついてる！
It's, it's sticking!
The glue is sticking to me.
熱そう！
That looks hot!
いつのまにか築地に...
Before we knew it, she built a...
見ないで！
Don't look!
もっと欲しくなってる！
She wants even more now!
よし！
Alright!
よいしょ、よいしょ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho!
何色がいい？何色がいい？
What color do you want? What color?
ブルー！青！そうめん食べたい！
Blue! Blue! I want to eat somen!
オッケー！
Okay!
いやあああ！
Noooo!
うわあああ！
Uwaaaa!
きゃあああ！
Kyaaaa!
盛り上がりすぎだろ、そっち！
You guys are getting way too hyped over there!
盛り上がりすぎだろ、みんな！
You're all way too hyped!
ねるねるねるね！ねるねるねるね！
Nerunerunerune! Nerunerunerune!
美味しいですか？
Is it delicious?
きゃあああ！
Kyaaaa!
食べれてない！
They're not even getting to eat it!
きゃあああ！
Kyaaaa!
本当のお祭りに来た気分になってきた！
It really feels like being at an actual festival!
あ、当たった！オッケー！
Ah, it hit! Okay!
オッケー！
Okay!
あれ？あれ？
Huh? What?
All right, and...
1、2、3、4、5...
1, 2, 3, 4, 5...
オッケー！
Okay!
あれ、これ何だっけ？
Wait, what was this again?
お箸もないから...
There aren't any chopsticks either...
It's gonna be blue.
ほら、笑ってこないで！
Hey, don't just laugh!
カップ2杯の水とトマトソースのもと...
Two cups of water and tomato sauce mix...
片手みんなヨーヨーさ...
Everyone with yo-yos in one hand...
今動画撮って...
Taking a video right now...
うわあああ！
Uwaaaa!
ちょっと！乱獲されてる！
Wait a sec! They're being overfished!
みこちさ、パスタ作れる...
Mikochi can make pasta...
イェーイ！
Yay!
Okay, one more! ワンモア！
Okay, one more! One more!
ワンモア！ラストワン！最後！
One more! Last one! Last one!
最後！オッケー！
Last one! Okay!
ワンモア！
One more!
緑がいいな！青い壁！
Green would be nice! A blue wall!
Oh, really?
Yeah, it's like separate 10 minutes...
お待たせしました！どうぞ！
Sorry to keep you waiting! Here you go!
おー！
Ooh!
Here we go!
全然取れてない！
You didn't get any at all!
手前を汚し...
Making a mess on this side...
また逃したのか！
Did you miss it again?!
そうめんこれだけやってさ、次のそうめんが流れてきたんだけど！
We barely touched this somen, and the next one is already flowing!
美味しそう！
Looks good!
そう！
Yeah!
ホワイトソースの粉が...
The white sauce powder...
取れない！
Can't get it!
大丈夫だよ！
It's alright!
そうめん！そうめん！
Somen! Somen!
そうめん食べた！
Ate the somen!
おい！お前ふざけんなよ！
Hey! Don't mess with me!
遅れアシストでさ...
With the delayed assist...
I didn't do it!
えー！そうめん泥棒いる！？
Wait! Is there a somen thief?!
アイスキャンディ難しい！難しい！
Making ice candy is so hard! Hard!
また流すよ！
I'm sending more down!
ねるねるねるね...
Nerunerunerune...
あ、ねるねる知ってる！
Ah, I know Neruneru!
落としちゃうんだ
You'll drop it.
行けー！すげー！
Go for it! Awesome!
そうめんハンターいる！
There's a somen hunter!
これで、甘酸っぱい...
With this, sweet and sour...
あー！落ちちゃった...
Ah! It fell...
美味しそう！
Looks delicious!
みおちゃん、そろそろさ、食べ物食べるの控えといてね！
Mio-chan, you should start holding off on eating food soon!
はーい
Okay~
確かに！確かに！
True! True!
これからビッグイベントが起こるんだから！
Because a big event is about to happen!
想像通り良い匂いだよ！
It smells as good as expected!
ね、賞品持ってきたよ！
Hey, I brought the prizes!
ん？え？
Hm? Eh?
チョコレートソース！
Chocolate sauce!
何？何の賞品？
What? A prize for what?
いや、あー！
No, aaah!
こっちでも用意してあったけど、みこちのもあるってことね！
We prepared some here too, but you mean Mikochi brought some too!
うん！
Yup!
え？何？みこちの賞品？
Eh? What? Mikochi's prize?
光ってる方から先渡すね！
I'll hand over the glowing one first!
気をつけてよ
Be careful.
よいしょ
Yoisho!
みおちゃーん
Mio-chan!
お、何か中華皿先回しね
Oh, looks like we're spinning the Chinese bowl first.
いつでも準備はでき…
Ready whenever!
これ誰なんだよ、業者
Who even is this, a vendor?
みおちゃん！
Mio-chan!
頑張れ！
Do your best!
あああ！そう！
Aaaah! Yeah!
ベエ・ザ・ラクーンガールの勝ち！
Bae the Raccoon Girl wins!
おー！どぅえー！
Whoa! Dwaaah!
いえーい！
Yaaay!
ファイブフィンガー
Five fingers!
いやあああ！
Noooo!
だめ！いやああ！
No! Noooo!
ヤバい、Bae！あああ！
This is bad, Bae! Aaargh!
あー！オールゲットー！
Ah! Got them all!
いえーい！
Yaaay!
ヤバい、ふぶきが…イエーイ！
Oh no, Fubuki is... Yay!
す、素晴らしいものだ
It-It's a wonderful thing.
完成！実に素晴らしい
Completed! Truly marvelous.
いやいやいや
No, no, no...
お、回るそうめんの…いやー！
Oh, the rotating somen... Nooo!
おおおー！
Ooooh!
あ、落っこちた！
Ah, it fell!
おおお！あああ！
Oooh! Aaaah!
誰だ？
Who's that?
よいしょ
Heave-ho.
ここにきて
Come over here.
お！みんないる！
Oh! Everyone is here!
やほー
Yahoo~
食べてもいいですか？
May I eat?
はい、どうぞ！いただきます！
Yes, go ahead! Dig in!
怪しいもの
Such a suspicious thing...
いやちょっとね、トラブルがあって
Well, there was a bit of trouble...
ちょっと待って、ガチでトラブル？
Wait a second, legit trouble?
ガチでトラ、ヤバい
Legit trou-, it's bad!
待って、私の足を…
Wait, my leg...
いやガチで
No, seriously...
美味しい！なんかぶどう味でパチパチしてて
Delicious! It tastes like grape and it's popping!
あ、よかった
Ah, thank goodness.
いや、すごい美味しい！アイスみたい
No, it's really delicious! Like ice cream!
いや、すごい美味しいよ！みこちゃんもちょっと食べてみて！
Yeah, it's super good! Miko-chan, try some too!
え、めっちゃ大丈夫？
Wait, it's totally fine?
はい、500カンパお願いします！ありがとね、来てくれて！
Alright, 500 campa, please! Thanks for coming!
はい、ホロライブ制覇！万歳！
Alright, Hololive conquered! Hurray!
花火ですね。なんかこれ、ベチョベチョしてる
Fireworks, huh. Somehow, this is all sticky.
スバルそれ、ちょっと…大暴れでした、初めの
For mine, that was a bit... It went totally wild at first.
え、美味しい！美味しかった？
Eh, it's good! - Was it good?
美味しいでちゅよ！すごい！
It's delicious! - Amazing!
これが…ネギが、乗るネギが…
This is... the scallions, the scallions that go on top...
ネギの箱でかい！一人に対して！
The scallion box is huge! For just one person!
笑うな！
Don't laugh!
どんなネギ入ってんのかな？
I wonder what kind of scallions are inside?
なんか顔がちょっと困ってるような表情で
Their faces have a slightly troubled expression.
ほら、区切るなって！
Look, stop partitioning it!
なんでそんな…ぶどう？ぶどう！ぶどうじゃん！
Why is it so... Grape? Grape! It really is grape!
グレープ！
Grape!
たまご…ルーちゃんも欲しい！
Egg... Lu-chan wants one too!
すっぱい、すっぱいからちょっと困ってる顔してるんだ
It's sour, that's why she has a troubled face.
今日の難易度高めとなっておりまして
The difficulty level today is quite high,
そうなんですね
Is that so.
ヨーヨーは…ベーちゃん、これ…
As for the yo-yos... Bae-chan, this...
結構ムズいけど、今Baeがファイブフィンガーを…
It's pretty hard, but Bae just did five fingers...
うわあああ！
Noooo!
なかなかムズいね
Quite difficult, isn't it.
ベタついてるだけだからめっちゃムズい
It's just sticky, so it's super hard.
ムズい？
Hard?
で、そのあとの綿あめ機は、さっきはじめがやったんだけど
And for the cotton candy machine, Hajime did it earlier, but...
なんかね、石みたいなの作ってました
somehow, she made something that looked like a stone.
石！？
A stone?!
で、流しそうめんもこれ回る
And this flowing somen spins around too.
え、行こうぞ！
Eh, let's go!
そう、回るんです！
Yes, it spins!
いらっしゃい、いらっしゃい！
Welcome, welcome!
ラスボスこれ？あ？
Is this the final boss? - Huh?
残り？
The leftovers?
これもね、なっちゃんのこれを…
This too, this one from Nat-chan...
じゃ、先にアレだね
Well, first let's do that.
こっちのヨーヨーしてみなよ
Try the yo-yo over here.
すごい！めっちゃムズいよ、それ
Amazing! - That's super difficult!
え、でもBae、ファイブフィンガー…
Eh, but Bae did five fingers...
はい！頑張ってー！
Yes! Do your best!
これもやりたい！
I want to do this too!
はい！
Yes!
なんか食ってる！めっちゃ、めっちゃ楽しい！
Someone's eating! Super, super fun!
ここに…アポロです！
Here is... an Apollo!
これが光るやつで、これが普通のヨーヨーです
This is the glowing one, and this is a regular yo-yo.
やばい、美味しそうだね
Oh man, looks delicious.
よいしょ！ナイス！
Heave-ho! Nice!
でも光るやつ欲しい
But I want a glowing one.
ピンク、ピンク！可愛い
Pink, pink! Cute.
ほら！あ、ナイス、ナイス！
Look! Ah, nice, nice!
流してる、流してる！引っかかってる、引っかかってる！
It's flowing, flowing! It's stuck, it's stuck!
あああ！
Aaaah!
好きな数…一気に行こう！
As many as you want... Let's do it all at once!
いやあああ！
Noooo!
ゲットだね
Got it, right?
え、いいの？流しすぎた
Eh, is it okay? Sent down too much.
回して…
Spin it...
えええ！逃したー！パスト！
Eeeeh! Missed it! - Passed!
なんで逃したの？
Why did you miss it?
結構な速さで…
It's quite fast...
イエイ！
Yay!
あ、取れた！
Ah, caught it!
嬉しい！
So happy!
そう、言ったね
Yeah, told you.
可愛い！お風呂で遊ぼう
Cute! Let's play with it in the bath.
真ん中に引っ掛けて…
Hook it in the middle...
チーズ？これ、普通のヨーヨー
Cheese? This is a normal yo-yo.
水色最高です！水色がいい！
Light blue is the best! Light blue is good!
よね！
Right!
ここに大量に入れて…
Putting a ton in here...
ああ！
Aah!
大丈夫、大丈夫！
It's fine, it's fine!
取れた！取れたー！
Got it! I got it!
取れた！ゲットー！
Got it! Grabbed it!
ナイス！はい、さあ！
Nice! Alright, now!
その奥は？全然違う…
What's further back? It's totally different...
痛い！あああ！
Ouch! Aaaah!
うわああ！
Waaaaah!
イエーイ！すごいな
Yay! Amazing.
さすがアイリス！
As expected of IRyS!
ああ！飴が！
Ah! The candy!
そうやって吸湿するから、こうやって…
Because it absorbs moisture, you have to do this...
飴が！
The candy!
ドロヘドロ女房…
Muddy mess wife...
りんご飴、アイリスの髪にくっついちゃった
The candy apple got stuck in IRyS's hair!
待って、待って、待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
髪にくっついちゃった
It got stuck in my hair!
あ、ティッシュを落としてくれました！ありがとう！
Ah, she dropped some tissues for me! Thank you!
そう、ティッシュ
Yeah, tissues.
流しそうめん早く入って！
Hurry up and get in the flowing somen!
お、あきら…
Oh, Akira...
誰が来るかな？
Who's gonna come?
ここからね
From right here.
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
あ、誰か来るんだ
Oh, someone's coming!
流します...
Sending it down...
そうめん
Somen.
This is a festival. It happened, this is happening.
It is, it is.
Alright.
Okay, the next is potato... え、次はポテト？
Okay, next is potato... Wait, next is potato?
え？次はポテト？
Huh? Next is potato?
あれ、そうめん回って... あ、止まりました。
Wait, the somen is circulating... Ah, it stopped.
あ、そういうこと？手前のやつ？
Ah, is that it? The one on this side?
はい！そうめんの準備OKです！
Okay! The somen is ready!
おーい！
Ooh!
これどうしたらいいの？全力で取れば？私流しそうめんやったことない！
What should I do? Grab it with everything I've got? I've never done flowing somen before!
ガチに、あの、べーが流しそうめん取りに来るから気をつけて
Seriously, Bae will come to snatch the flowing somen, so watch out.
え、横取りされる？！
Wait, she's gonna snatch it?!
それだけ気をつけてください
Just be careful of that.
オッケー！
Okay!
莉々華です！こんにちはー！
It's Ririka! Hello~!
レッツゴー！
Let's go!
ヤバい、ヤバい！
Oh no, oh no!
まずいまずいまずい！
This is bad, bad, bad!
莉々華！柵を越えるな！
Ririka! Don't cross the barrier!
え、だって取られるんだもん！
But she's gonna steal it!
邪魔すんなー！
Don't get in my way!
ピカチュウより前に箸出すな！バッドマナーだからな！
Don't put your chopsticks ahead of Pikachu! That's bad manners!
バッドマナーw
Bad manners, lol.
そうだよ、それそうめんバッドマナーだよ、それ！
Yeah, that's bad somen manners right there!
よいしょ...
Heave-ho...
はい！
Here!
流れてない！まだ流れてない！
It's not flowing! It hasn't started flowing yet!
待って、すでにいるもん！
Wait, she's already right there!
それはそう、我が陣営にちょっとノーデス！
That's true, in our camp she's got no chill!
うわー！べーさんも早すぎだよ！
Whoa! Bae-san, you're way too fast too!
ポテト... ポテトの匂い...
Potato... smells like potato...
流します...
Sending it down...
ポテトの匂い...
Smells like potato...
大丈夫？
You okay?
熱い！熱い！やばい！
Hot! It's hot! Oh no!
流します！
Sending it down!
いらっしゃい！
Come on down!
いや、これはちょっとね...
Well, this is a bit...
莉々華はなんであんな戦ってたの？
Why was Ririka fighting so hard like that?
奪われてた...
It was being stolen...
いただきます！
Down the hatch!
大葉を入れました！
I put perilla leaves in!
いいやん！
Nice!
大葉がいっちゃん美味いからな
Perilla is the most delicious thing, after all.
これ、取り合いたくない？
Doesn't this make you want to battle over it?
違いますよ！
No way!
でも絶対その下手にいる方が...
But definitely being downstream is...
あああー！
Aaaah!
可愛いね
So cute.
危ないよ、もう！
That's dangerous, geez!
よくない、これが！
This is no good!
前屈み禁止にしてください！
Please ban leaning forward!
前屈み禁止？
Ban leaning forward?
前屈み禁止！でしょ？
Leaning forward is banned, right?
スバルを追放する気か？！
Are you trying to banish Subaru?!
お前がやってるんだよ！
You're the one doing it!
全然違うとこ見てない？
Aren't you looking at a completely different place?
フブキ先輩のところ行ってみる？
Should we visit Fubuki-senpai's stall?
ヤッホー！
Yahoo!
オッケー、ありがとう！
Okay, thank you!
すごい美味しい、これ！美味しいでしょ？
This is super delicious! Good, right?
そうめん大満足！
Super satisfied with the somen!
Yo-yo booth, we are closing for the night.
ええー？！
Eeeeh?!
え、ヨーヨーのやり方教えてください！
Wait, please teach me how to do the yo-yo!
え、みこち取ってないの？
Wait, Mikochi, you haven't fished one?
取るだけ？
Just grab it?
そう、1つ取って、で、欲しいやつを...
Yeah, grab one, and then for the one you want...
ちょっとだけ食べて、すっごい美味しかった！
I had a little taste and it was so delicious!
オッケー！やるぜ！
Okay! Let's do this!
莉々華、こういう細かい作業マジ得意だから
Ririka is seriously good at delicate tasks like this.
いっぱいないよ、こんなにいっぱいそうめん
There isn't that much somen...
どれにしようかな〜
Which one should I choose~?
何て書いてある？莉々華、読め！
What does it say? Ririka, read it!
前屈み禁止！
No leaning forward!
急に離すとこうやって... やだ！仲間はずれにされてるー！
If you let go suddenly, like this... No! I'm being left out!
急に離すと...
If you suddenly let go...
あ、こうすればいいのか！こうやって...
Ah, this is how to do it! Like this...
うわ！やば！
Whoa! Oh gosh!
ヨーヨーゲット！
Yo-yo get!
プロ？上手いね！
Are you a pro? You're good!
じゃあこれも狙っちゃおうかな
Then maybe I'll aim for this one too.
重そうだけど...
Looks heavy, though...
せーの！
Ready, set...
前屈み禁止だから...
Since leaning forward is banned...
ガニ股になってる！
She's standing bow-legged!
めっちゃガニ股に！
Totally bow-legged!
めっちゃ酸っぱい！
Super sour!
あ、凍ってるこれ！
Ah, this is frozen!
こうやってあげて... おおー！
Lift it like this... Ooooh!
あ、でもちぎれたー！
Ah, but it snapped!
みこゲットー！イエーイ！
Miko got it! Yay!
え、これどうしたらいいの？もらっていいってこと？
Wait, what should I do with this? I can keep it?
やったー！
Yay!
きれい！きれい！えええ？！
Pretty! So pretty! Huh?!
めちゃくちゃ飛んでくる！
It's flying everywhere!
危ない！
Watch out!
命の... 命の灯火が...
The flame... the spark of life is...
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
ぐるぐる回るね。でかいよね？
It's spinning around. It's huge, isn't it?
圧倒的大成功！
An overwhelming huge success!
愛情を込めることだったんだ
It was all about pouring love into it.
いいよ！
Nice!
ダムダムダム...
Dum, dum, dum...
はい、できたー！
All done!
すごーい！
Amazing!
ナイスー
Nice~
見える？
Can you see it?
なんかみこちのなんかねるねるねるね...
Compared to Mikochi's Nerunerunerune...
ふざけんなよ！
Don't mess with me!
比べるとちょっと...
If you compare them, it's a bit...
ふざけんなよ！
Don't mess with me!
そして...
And then...
ピロピロが出た
The little party horn came out!
かわいい！
So cute!
かわいいね
It really is cute.
ナイス！
Nice!
どうした？どうした？
What's wrong? What happened?
はい、じゃあ、そうめん屋閉店するよー！
Alright, the somen stand is closing up!
はーい！
Okay!
じゃあ、新しいアトラクション...
Now then, the next attraction...
こんにちはー！
Hello!
パパーン！
Ta-da!
あ、両方取れた！
Ah, I caught both!
おー！すごーい！
Oh! Amazing!
え、美味しそう！え、待って、私もやってみます！
Looks yummy! Wait, let me try too!
ちょっと砂糖に...
Put some in the sugar...
あ、いっぱい入れ...
Ah, put a lot in...
いや、いいなあ
Ah, that's so nice.
オッケー、水...
Okay, water...
え、いくつ、何色でもいいですか？
Um, how many, can it be any color?
いろは、まさか焼いてきたか！？
Iroha, did you actually bake them?!
え！？え！？
What?! What?!
ねるねるねるねできたー！
The Nerunerunerune is done!
キャンディパフキャンディみたいな、マックスキャンディ？
Like Candy Puff candy, Max Candy?
オッケー！いただきます！
Okay! Let's eat!
いろはのところ見...うわ、いろはうまい！
Look at Iroha's... Wow, Iroha is so good!
みんなで作ってたんだよ
We were making them all together.
あいつなんかワンチャンクッキー焼いてから来るらしいけど間に合うんか？みたいな
Like, "She might bake cookies before coming, but will she make it in time?"
そこをあえて...
She dared to take that chance...
あ、そうなんだ！
Oh, really!
え、みんなに見せてあげてよ、なんかあの...え、でも今そっち行ったのか
Hey, show everyone... wait, did she head over there now?
え、かわいい！
Wow, cute!
かわいい！
So cute!
鬼かわいい！
Insanely cute!
じゃあ、そうめん屋閉店しちゃったんだけど、ヨーヨー屋さんと、あの...
Well, the somen stand closed down, but the yo-yo shop and, um...
わたあめ屋さんはまだ空いてるよ！
The cotton candy shop is still open!
おいしい！すごくおいしい！
Delicious! It's super delicious!
ねるねるねるねいいね！
Nerunerunerune is great!
あめとねるねるねるね、おいしい！
The candy and Nerunerunerune are delicious!
コンビが美味しい！
The combo is delicious!
イェーイ！It's so yummy!
Yay! It's so yummy!
よかったです！
Glad you like it!
いろはクッキーみんなに見せてあげた？
Did you show the Iroha cookies to everyone?
食べたーい！
I wanna eat!
スバルも食べたい！いろはクッキー！
Subaru wants to eat too! Iroha cookies!
あ、おいでー！
Ah, come on over!
私、りんご飴食べていいですか？
Can I have an apple candy?
マジ！？あんの！？
Seriously?! There's one?!
え、お持ち帰り用セットみたいの...
Like a takeout set...
でも冷蔵庫入れた方が...
But it's better to put it in the fridge...
えー、食べてみたい！
Eh, I want to try it!
教えて、教えて！
Tell me, tell me!
これ、あれだよね？
This is that, right?
いや、美味しい！コンビにしたい！
Ah, so delicious! I want to make combos!
どのコンビがいいの？
Which combo do you want?
あるよ！
We have it!
あ、じゃあこれを...
Ah, then this one...
トッピング失礼します！
Adding toppings, excuse me!
ねるねるやば！
Neruneru is crazy!
ねるねるコンビできた！
The Neruneru combo is ready!
ね、美味しい！よし、コンビ！
Right? Delicious! Alright, combo!
オッケー、オッケー！
Okay, okay!
じゃあこれで...オッケー、ピント合ってる！
Then with this... Okay, it's in focus!
ね、しっとりクッキー美味しい！
Right? Soft cookies are delicious!
これやばいね、クズが降ってくるの、ナイス！
This is crazy, the crumbs raining down, nice!
トントントンってトッピング...
Tap-tap-tap, the toppings...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
マジでやばい！スバルが大変なことになってる！
Seriously crazy! Subaru's in quite a situation!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
オッケー、みんな見て！みこちのねるねるねるねと、えっと...
Okay, everyone look! Mikochi's Nerunerunerune and, um...
りんご飴！
Apple candy!
Look, look! It's a combination!
いろはクッキー！
Iroha cookie!
これ、からむすび？
Is this Karamubi?
味見、味見！がんばって！
Taste test, taste test! Go for it!
これ、ディップしてる！ディップしてる！
Look, she's dipping it! Dipping it!
ポコロクッキー！
Pokoro cookie!
もらったー！
I got one!
やばい、妖怪食い散らかしがいる！
Oh no, there's a littering food phantom!
いいよ、いっぱい食べていいよ
Go ahead, eat as much as you want.
どれから食べていいか...
Which one should I eat first...
あ、水で作ったアイス！出来上がった！
Ah, the ice cream made with water! It's done!
え、あの伝説の...
Eh, that legendary...
食べますか？アイリスのアイス！
Wanna eat? IRyS's ice cream!
え、いいの！？
Wait, really?!
アイスじゃない？バナナ？
Isn't it ice cream? Banana?
かわいい！
So cute!
大丈夫？
Is it okay?
おいしいよね！
It's good, right!
かわいい！
Cute!
誰のこれ？
Whose is this?
チョコソースもチェリーもある！
There's chocolate sauce and cherry too!
結構時間かけて作ったんですよ、アイリスだから！
I spent quite some time making it, because it's IRyS!
うまーい！
Delicious!
You put so much time and effort into it, right?
Yeah, thank you!
愛情も込めて！
Made with love too!
じゃあ、ちょっとそろそろ...
Well then, pretty soon...
いただきまーす！
Bon appétit!
伝説のイベント、みおちゃんが来たらやりたいと思います！
We want to hold the legendary event once Mio-chan arrives!
甘ーい！うまい！やったー！
So sweet! Yummy! Yay!
今から何をするかを説明します！
I'll explain what we're going to do now!
スバルも食べたい！
Subaru wants to eat too!
いいよ、食べて！
Sure, go ahead and eat!
オッケー！
Okay!
それでは、えー、夏祭り最後のイベントになります！
Well then, uh, this is the final event of the Summer Festival!
最後のイベントは、みおちゃんのワンワンレースです！
The final event is Mio-chan's Bow-Wow Race!
ワンワンレース！
Bow-Wow Race!
何をするかというと、それではカメラをオンにします。オン！
As for what we do, let's turn on the camera. On!
あー！
Ahhh!
トワちゃん、みおは？
Towa-chan, where's Mio?
下に並んじゃってるから
She's lined up down there.
本当だ！
You're right!
これは何をするかというとですね、今からみおちゃんが、犬のおもちゃと競走します！
As for what this is, Mio-chan is going to race against toy dogs!
え！？やば！
What?! Crazy!
今ね、こうやってね、皆さん見えますか？ワンちゃんが...
Right now, like this, can everyone see? The dogs...
かわいい！
Cute!
見える！見えます！
I see them! We can see them!
かわいい！
So cute!
そうなんです！このワンちゃんは、この赤い線まで走ります！
That's right! These doggies will run to this red line!
おおー！
Ooh!
そして、みおちゃんはここから300m走ります！
And Mio-chan will run 300 meters from here!
ええー！？
What?!
で、誰が一番最初に着くかをみんな予想してください
And everyone, please predict who will reach the finish first!
当たった人は...
Whoever gets it right...
We have the right...
おおー！
Whoa!
The doggy has to cross the red line.
いけた？
Did it make it?
おー！
Oh!
流れるー！すごーい！
It's flowing! Amazing!
犬5匹いるぞ！
There are five dogs!
もうデコられてる
They're already decorated!
もう大丈夫ね？
Are we all set now?
はい
Yes.
電池が入ってるよね？でもミオ先輩は電池が入ってないから大丈夫
There are batteries inside, right? But Mio-senpai has no batteries, so she's fine!
おー！
Oh!
エントリーナンバー1の犬...
Entry Number 1 dog...
Almost... Entry Number 1...
あ、英語で説明してもらっていい？
Ah, could you explain in English?
We have reached the final event of today's Summer Festival!
We have now reached the... え、ナンバーワン...
We have now reached the... uh, number one...
ミオちゃん、走る準備...
Mio-chan, ready to run...
ミオちゃん！スカートがめくれてるよ！
Mio-chan! Your skirt is flipped up!
あーー！
Aaaah!
ミオちゃん！スカートがめくれてるよ！
Mio-chan! Your skirt is flipped up!
見えてない！
We can't see anything!
The event is: Run Mio-sha, Wan-Wan Race!
へぇー！おおー！
Ooh!
On the screen, as you can see, they'll be racing against Mio-sha...
おー！
Oh!
One out of four if they reach the red line first...
ミオちゃん！スカートがめくれてるー！
Mio-chan! Your skirt is flipped up!
Mio-senpai has to run 300 meters!
Please place your bets on who you think will win! If you guess correctly, there will be a prize!
おおー！
Whoa!
絶対ミオ先輩の勝ち！
Mio-senpai will definitely win!
その通りー！
That's right!
ちなみに、ワンちゃんはどんな感じで動くかって言うと...
By the way, as for how the doggies move...
え、ワンちゃん見たい
Oh, I want to see the doggies.
え、早っ！早っ！
Wait, that's fast! So fast!
最初はワンワンワンワンって... かわいいー！
At first it goes "woof woof woof"... So cute!
じゃ、エントリーナンバー1、なんかこのすごいふわふわしてる白い犬
So, Entry No. 1: this super fluffy white dog.
はい
Yes.
結構早いです
It's pretty fast.
ちょっと固まった
It froze a bit.
この犬がほしい
I want this dog.
ほしい、やめてほしい
"I want it"? Please don't say that.
あ、かわいい
Ah, cute.
エントリーナンバー2、え、ちょっとキャバリアっぽい、なんかころねっぽいヤツ
Entry No. 2, uh, kinda like a Cavalier, kinda like Korone.
あー、かわいい！
Ah, cute!
決めてる
I've decided.
そしてエントリーナンバー3
And Entry No. 3...
いぬち
Inuchi.
いぬち。みこちのいぬち
Inuchi. Mikochi's Inuchi.
いぬちー！がんばれー！
Inuchi! Do your best!
そしてエントリーナンバー4、柴犬
And Entry No. 4, a Shiba Inu.
うわっ！
Whoa!
2号やばい！
No. 2 is insane!
やばい、2号やばい！2号やばい！
Oh no, No. 2 is insane! No. 2 is insane!
早い！
So fast!
2号が早いか。早いね
No. 2 is fast, huh. It really is.
ということで... ちなみにこれ、あの、あれね
So with that... by the way, this is, um...
いぬちー！
Inuchi!
あの、こっから落ちたら、もう即アウト
If they fall off from here, it's an instant disqualification.
ああー、なるほど！
Ah, I see!
うん、落ちたら即アウトで、えー、誰が一番早いでしょうかというレースになります
Yeah, falling off is instant out, and the race is to see who's fastest.
シュールだね
That's surreal.
え？4号... 4号がまっすぐ...
Eh? No. 4... No. 4 goes straight...
4号はまっすぐかな。まあそれも運ということで
Maybe No. 4 goes straight? Well, that's up to luck too.
それではちょっと皆さん予想してください。ちなみにミオちゃん、100mの...
Now then, everyone please make your predictions. By the way, Mio-chan, for 100 meters...
100m何秒？
How many seconds for 100 meters?
はい。あ、ちょっと待ってください
Yes. Ah, please wait a moment.
Let's see...
300って言ってたんですけど、300は無理なので150になりました
I said 300, but 300 is impossible, so it became 150.
あ、150ね！
Ah, 150!
150！
150!
大体150mくらいね
Roughly 150 meters, right.
50 miles?!
17秒とか？
Like 17 seconds?
え、そんなかかります？100m。100m17？
Eh, does it take that long? 100 meters. 17 for 100 meters?
え、17？
Eh, 17?
え、そんなもんじゃないですか？
Isn't that about normal?
あ、そうなんだ。17、18...
Ah, is it? 17, 18...
あれ？50mが10とかだっけ？
Wait, was 50 meters like 10 seconds?
そう、50m遅いと10
Yeah, 50 meters if you're slow is 10.
そっか、小学生で7秒とかぐらいか
I see, elementary schoolers do about 7 seconds?
7秒クソ早い！え、そうなんだ
7 seconds is insanely fast! Wait, really?
え、ちなみにワンワンは、えーとね、まあ...
By the way, for the doggies, um, well...
え、これワンワンのさ、タイム言っていい？
Can I say the doggies' time?
はい
Yes.
ワンワンはゴールまで行くのに、まあ平均30秒くらい
For the doggies to reach the goal, it takes about 30 seconds on average.
へぇーー！
Heeeh!
ま、早いヤツもいるし、ちょっと...
Well, some are fast, and...
ただ...
However...
そんなに頑張れないかも
I might not be able to push myself that hard...
いや、頑張ってくださいよ！戦ってくださいよ！
No, please do your best! Put up a fight!
あちぃ！
It's so hot!
お腹いっぱいかな
Are you full?
あー
Ahhh...
ちなみにあの、ミオちゃんが今何メートル走ってるっていうのは、フブちゃんが口頭で説明してくれます
By the way, Fubu-chan will verbally announce how many meters Mio-chan has run.
はい
Yes.
なるほど
I see.
150mくらいなんだけど、ここのメーターであの測っていて、はい
It's around 150 meters, and it's measured with this meter here, yes.
大体ウチが30秒くらい走った、えっと距離をあの測りましたので
We measured the distance I ran in roughly 30 seconds,
その距離をゴール地点としております
so that distance is set as the goal.
はい！おおー！
Got it! Ooh!
はい。それでは皆さん予想してください。どの犬が、え、1位なのか決まったら...
All right. Now everyone, please guess. Once you've decided which dog will get 1st place...
はい！ミオ先輩！
Yes! Mio-senpai!
あ、神
Ah, God.
え、ウチ？
Wait, me?
犬ね！
The dogs!
3番のいぬちにベット
Betting on No. 3 Inuchi.
ねねは？
What about Nene?
2番、キャバリア、ワン！
No. 2, Cavalier, woof!
じゃ予想のやつを...
Then make your predictions...
いや、ミオ先輩！ミオ先輩にぶっぱするからな！
No, Mio-senpai! I'm going all in on Mio-senpai!
いや、犬だから！犬！
No, it's the dogs! Dogs!
犬？
Dogs?
ミオちゃん
Mio-chan.
ミオ先輩！
Mio-senpai!
出来レースのようにミオ先輩が勝つんでしょ？
Mio-senpai's gonna win like it's a fixed race anyway, right?
本当に？
Really?
もちろん
Of course.
大丈夫かな
Will it be okay?
みんな決まったら...
Once everyone has decided...
じゃ、みこち3ね
Then Mikochi takes 3.
ミオが勝ちそうだけど、なんか2の犬がやりそう
Mio seems like she'll win, but feel like Dog No. 2 will do it.
一生懸命走ります
I'll run as hard as I can!
はい、ラミィは2番のキャバリア
Yes, Lamy takes No. 2 Cavalier.
キャバリアね。何で？
Cavalier, huh. Why?
ころねだから
Because it's Korone.
あ、ころねだからね。えーと
Ah, because of Korone. Okay...
1番のプードル
No. 1 Poodle.
ちょっと待って、え、ミオちゃん誰にもいなくて笑う
Wait a sec, laughing because nobody picked Mio-chan!
ええーー？！
Eeeh?!
ミオしゃ全然...
Mio-sha got nobody...
ちょっとミオちゃんは、ちょっと信用しないマウントで
We're taking the "we don't quite trust Mio-chan" stance.
ええー？！
Eeeh?!
え、こよりは？
What about Koyori?
えー、迷う！結構落ちたら...
Uh, I'm torn! If it falls off...
2番で！
No. 2!
あー、ミオちゃんではない。2番。2番ね。
Ah, not Mio-chan. No. 2. No. 2, right?
2番！
No. 2!
ナンバー？
Number?
ござるは？
What about Gozaru?
ミオ先輩に全部ベット！
All bets on Mio-senpai!
おー！賭けて賭けて賭けて！
Oh, place your bets, place your bets!
何番？
Which number?
リリカもう、ミオ先輩足ちぎれるまで走ってくださいー！
Ririka says, Mio-senpai, please run until your legs tear off!
ぎゃーー！
Aaargh!
え、チームENは？
What about Team EN?
えっと、ミオ先輩絶対勝つ！
Um, Mio-senpai is definitely gonna win!
フワモコは？
FuwaMoco?
そう、ミオ先輩でしょ！
Yeah, obviously Mio-senpai!
ミオ先輩？！ありがとうー！
Mio-senpai?! Thank you!
え、ハコスは？
And Hakos?
いや、ミオ先輩でしょーが！
I mean, it's gotta be Mio-senpai!
イェーーイ！
Yeahhh!
ネリッサは？
Nerissa?
ミオ先輩！
Mio-senpai!
おおーー！
Ooh!
まだ言、言ってない人いる？
Anyone who hasn't said it yet?
もう言った全員？
Has everyone said it?
全員言った！
Everyone's said it!
スバル先輩、4番どんな犬ですか？
Subaru-senpai, what kind of dog is number 4?
4番雰囲気強いよ、今。
Number 4 has a strong vibe right now.
え、じゃあ...
Eh, in that case...
じゃあ4！
Then number 4!
ちょっと待って、JP誰もミオちゃんに入れてないのヤバイだろ！
Wait a minute, isn't it bad that no one from JP is betting on Mio-chan?!
入れてる、入れてる、入れてる！
I am, I am, I'm betting on her!
誰が入れてんの？
Who's betting on her?
え、じゃあフブちゃん、フブちゃん！
Wait, then Fubu-chan, Fubu-chan!
え、ミオしか勝たんが？
Huh, Mio is the only one who can win, right?
ミオしか勝たんて
Mio is the best.
あ、そうだよね！当たり前だよな！
Ah, right! Of course!
当たり前！何言ってんだ！
Obviously! What are you talking about?!
それじゃあ、えーっとレース開始したいと思います。位置について、用意ドンでやりたいと思いますので、じゃあ、
Well then, let's get the race started. We'll do it on "On your mark, get set, go!", so...
ハコス、位置について用意してもらっていい？
Hakos, could you get them ready on the starting line?
え、待って、これ被ってたらどうなるんですか？私達が勝った時にまたそこで殴り合いが発生するんですか？
Wait, what happens if bets overlap? If we win, will a fist fight break out there again?
いやいや、そんな別に、あの1位で当てた人全員景品あるから。
No, no, everyone who guesses 1st place correctly gets a prize.
全員？！やったーー！
Everyone?! Yay!!
ありますならいいですね
If so, that's great!
はい、OK。ここね。
Okay, got it. Right here.
それでは、ミオちゃんも怪我しないように準備してね。
Alright then, Mio-chan, get ready so you don't hurt yourself.
はい！本気で走る準備はできてます！
Yes! I'm ready to run with all my might!
行けるぞミオ！
You can do it, Mio!
それじゃ、よし。犬、赤い線に準備しました！
Alright then, good. The dogs are lined up on the red line!
準備しました！
All ready!
はい！
Okay!
それでは行きます！
Here we go!
位置について！
On your mark!
よーい、スタート！
Get set, go!
がんばれ！がんばれ！4番！4番！
Go, go, go! Number 4! Number 4!
4番行け！ミオ！ミオ！
Go, number 4! Mio! Mio!
ミオ！行け行け行け！
Mio! Go, go, go!
ミオ！ミオ！ミオ！ミオ！ミオ！
Mio! Mio! Mio! Mio! Mio!
ぎゃああーーー！
Aaaaaaah!
どうした？！ええ？！
What happened?! What?!
どうなったの？！嘘でしょ？！
What happened?! No way!
ミオさんとよーい同時に？
Right at the start with Mio-san?!
ミオちゃんが死んだ！
Mio-chan died!
ミオちゃん？！倒れた！
Mio-chan?! She collapsed!
白と、4のサロンドで、あ、サロンド勝った！
It's between White and 4, Salon de... Ah, Salon de won!
ミオ、息してる？
Mio, are you breathing?
ミオ先輩、もう一回走れますか？倒れてますけど...
Mio-senpai, can you run one more time? You're collapsed, though...
い、息してる...
I-I'm breathing...
大丈夫か？！
Are you okay?!
救急車ーー！
Ambulance!!
じゃあ4番でサロンドですね？
So number 4, Salon de won, right?
大丈夫ですか？
Are you alright?
ミオちゃん大丈夫？
Mio-chan, you okay?
ねねも走りたい！
Nene wants to run too!
何言ってんだよ！
What are you talking about?!
走ってないだけ... 無理だろ
She wasn't even running... No way.
ミオさん大丈夫ですか？
Mio-san, are you alright?
これ絶対に4番の方が有利だろ！
Number 4 definitely has the advantage here!
4番最強だね
Number 4 is the strongest, huh?
一回も転んでないからね
Since it didn't trip once.
Aki no message drink call...
Aki's message drink call...
ラスト、ラストワンだよ。ラストワン、ラスト
It's the last one! Last one, last.
行けるぞミオ！
You can do it, Mio!
No. I don't like the smell of soda.
じゃあ皆さん、もう一回じゃあ4番だと思った人、手挙げてください。はい。
Alright everyone, if you think number 4 will win this time, raise your hand. Go.
はい！はい！
Here! Me!
Who thinks number 4 is gonna win? They're doing it one more time.
Who thinks number four is gonna win? They're doing it one more time.
あれ？あれ？戻った？
Huh? Huh? Did it go back?
戻っちゃった！
It went back!
機械だからと思って...
Thinking "because it's a machine..."
機械だからね
Well, it is a machine.
じゃあ4番の人、はい！ / はーーい！
Then for number 4, say "Here"! / Here!
えー、スバル、ねねち、こより...
Okay: Subaru, Nenechi, Koyori...
これでいいの？敵的なやつら？
Is that good? Are they the rivals?
大丈夫
That's fine.
大丈夫ね。じゃあそのほか、ミオちゃんね。
All good, then. And the rest are on Mio-chan, right?
待って、時間くれよ！ / 何で？
Wait, give me some time! / Why?
じゃああの、1分休憩で。
Okay then, a one-minute break.
1分？！休憩？
One minute?! A break?
ストレッチ！ストレッチ！頑張ってストレッチ、ミオちゃん！
Stretch! Stretch! Do your best stretching, Mio-chan!
うーー / 頑張って、頑張って！
Oogh... / Hang in there, hang in there!
大変だ。まさかサロンドに去ると思わんやん！
Oh boy. Who would've thought she'd be bested by Salon de!
でもミオちゃん、ミオちゃんあんなに「うちワンワンレースするんだよね」ってあんなキラキラした目で語ってたじゃないか！
But Mio-chan, you were telling us with such sparkling eyes, "We're gonna do a puppy race, you know!" weren't you?!
こんなに走るとは思わなかった...
I didn't think I'd be running this much...
頑張れミオちゃん！頑張れ！
Hang in there, Mio-chan! You can do it!
因みにこの企画ね、ミオちゃん考案だから。
By the way, this whole event was Mio-chan's idea.
自業自得やん！
It's totally her own fault!
カメラ持って走れや、ヤバイ
Running while holding a camera, that's crazy.
ふくらはぎが... ここに来て、足が攣った
My calves... My leg cramped up just now.
なんか言ってる
She's saying something.
動かす...
I'll move it...
おおーーー！
Ooooh!!
え、立った？！
Wait, she stood up?!
すごい！見せて見せて
Amazing! Show us, show us!
今ね、ミオちゃんが休憩してる間にね...
Now, while Mio-chan is taking a break...
おお、すげえ！
Whoa, awesome!
Aki no message drink call... / I'm not gonna drink it.
Aki's message drink call... / I'm not gonna drink it.
終わったらね、サロンドね。 / Is anyone gonna make it?
Once it's over, right, Salon de. / Is anyone gonna make it?
It became a little bit spicy to begin.
I don't want to make it. I made the ones that I wanted to make.
I made a Borgor.
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
やめ！やめー！ヒューヒュー！
Stop! Stop it! Woohoo!
買っちゃった
I bought it.
じゃあ100万円で！
Then that'll be one million yen!
ふざけんなお前！
Don't mess with me!
参加賞は？
What about the participation prize?
えっと、参加賞は...
Um, the participation prize is...
参加賞です
Here is your participation prize.
あ、でもキャンディ入ってないですね
Ah, but there's no candy in it.
お前参加賞まんざらでもねえよ！
You're actually not unhappy with the prize at all!
味のさっぱりアイス
Refreshing flavored ice.
からし飴もたっぷり！
And plenty of mustard candy!
ええ〜！
Ehh?!
え、食べれんの？
Wait, is that even edible?
はい、それでは締めますよ、あなた達！
All right, let's wrap it up, everyone!
はい！
Okay!
今回の夏フェス、ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much for joining our Summer Festival!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
え、待って、指がっつり見えてヤバい！
Wait, your fingers are totally visible, this is bad!
それではね、せっかくなんでね、今日ね、お店屋さんしてくれた、まずフブちゃんどうでしたか、今日は？
Now then, since we're here, Fubu-chan, who ran a booth today, how was it for you?
楽しかったワン！いぬちぇん！
It was so fun, woof! Dog change!
楽しかったワンですか。はい、ありがとうございます！
"So fun, woof," was it? All right, thank you very much!
じゃあ、あの、夏祭り主催に対して、一言どうぞ！
Now then, a word to the Summer Festival organizer, go ahead!
スババー！
Subabaaa!
ねえ、その雑なやつやめて！駄目駄目、やめて！
Hey, stop being so lazy with it! No, no, stop that!
楽しかった！ありがとうございます！
It was so fun! Thank you so much!
はい！
All right!
じゃ、そして、走ったワンちゃんみおしゃ、どうでしたか、今日は？
And next, Miosha, the dog who ran, how was it for you today?
たくさんの人が来てくれて、凄く嬉しかったですわ！
So many people came to visit, I was terribly delighted!
あー、よかったですねー！
Ah, that's wonderful!
遊びに来てくれてありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much for coming to hang out!
イエーイ！
Yay!
それでは最後はおつホロ夏祭りで終わりたいと思いまーす！
Now then, we'd like to close out with "Otsu-Holo Summer Festival"!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい！それでは行きますよ。せーの！
All right! Here we go. Ready, set...
おつホロ夏祭りー！
Otsu-Holo Summer Festival!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
チャンネル登録、高評価お願いします！
[Please subscribe and like my channel!]